<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Kulp Family Travels</title>
    <link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="" />
    <updated>2025-01-01T16:01:29-06:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>arian</name>
    </author>
    <id></id>

    <entry>
        <title>Makhwapheni</title>
        <author>
            <name>Arian and Karen</name>
        </author>
        <link href="/makhwapheni/index.html"/>
        <id>/makhwapheni/index.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-16T09:08:40-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Makhwapheni (mock-wah-pay’-nee) – Temporary lover After working hard alongside the Swazis the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><em>Makhwapheni (mock-wah-pay’-nee) – Temporary lover</em></p>
<p>After working hard alongside the Swazis the past almost 8 months to assist with building up their medical records system, the plug has been pulled.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/52/MicrosoftTeams-image.jpg" alt="I think this picture says it all&amp;#8230;" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/52/responsive/MicrosoftTeams-image-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/52/responsive/MicrosoftTeams-image-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/52/responsive/MicrosoftTeams-image-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/52/responsive/MicrosoftTeams-image-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>The journey has been hard at times. Coming as the latest in a line of various volunteers and other organizations, it’s hard to assure people that we are there to help and won’t just start some crazy new thing and then run off. Our focus has been to try to add features to their EMR (electronic medical records system) and update some of their processes to enable them to offer the care the population needs (by their invitation and working on their priorities). Coming from a different background, our experience includes things that haven’t been tried here so we worked to train/mentor local people so they would be able to utilize these techniques for the long haul. The Peace Corps’ definition of success includes leaving an organization in a state that they don’t need you anymore. If we can’t leave without things falling apart, we’ve failed.</p>
<p>Makhwapheni (from the post heading) apparently means “temporary lover.” There are always (in every environment) people who are resistant to change, looking for a reason to discount new ideas. Makhwapheni implies that since we’re just the most recent in a string of “lovers,” we don’t need to be taken seriously. This general idea also leads to questions about extending our time to get more done. At this point, we weren’t really interested in extending though since the goal was to pass along knowledge and perspective, then get back to family and friends. Now it’s out of our hands regardless and we can’t even finish our commitment. That’s really the worst possible case since we weren’t able to get things to the point of hand-off, and it basically validates their initial worries. It’s all kind of surreal at the moment.</p>
<p>We’ll write another post soon with more details. At the moment we don’t have any more information to give. Volunteers are all waiting at their posts for further instructions, packing and reflecting. Stay tuned…</p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Coronavirus</title>
        <author>
            <name>Damian and Lilly</name>
        </author>
        <link href="/coronavirus/index.html"/>
        <id>/coronavirus/index.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-29T07:30:17-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Hello everyone! I’m writing this brief post to give everyone an update&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Hello everyone!</p>
<p>I’m writing this brief post to give everyone an update on the situation here in Japan. Some of you may have heard that Abe Shinzo, Japan’s prime minister, made an announcement last week that all of the schools in Japan would be closed for the next several weeks. It was really a suggestion, but as my school district decided to close school, you may be wondering what all this means for Damian and I.</p>
<p>For the most part, our day-to-day doesn’t really change. Damian isn’t affected at all, as he works from home, and I’m actually still going to work. School is closed for the kids, but teachers are actually still required to go in.</p>
<p>So, for the next month until the new school year, I’m going to be spending a lot of time at my desk. I will probably be doing prep, Japanese language study, and discreet reading. In all honesty, I’m probably going to be extremely bored for the next month until the new school year starts (The school year starts in April in Japan). However, I will still be working and it’s pretty much business as usual.</p>
<p>Damian and I are doing fine, and we’re mildly amused with the antics of some people overreacting to the situation.</p>
<p>Look forward to some older posts that we’ve been working on! We’ll be sure to keep everyone updated with the goings on out here.</p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Home at Last</title>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriel and Kendrea</name>
        </author>
        <link href="/home-at-last/index.html"/>
        <id>/home-at-last/index.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-16T05:46:30-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    We arrived in Corvallis a month and a half ago, and wow,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>We arrived in Corvallis a month and a half ago, and wow, it feels like a lot of time has passed.</p>
<h2>Looking Back on Nepal</h2>
<p>It would be nice if living in Nepal taught us the meaning of life. It’s not quite so straightforward, though. Here are the real results of our time abroad:</p>
<ul>
<li>By living in a very different place, we simply learned more about how the world can function. It turns out that near-anarchy (no traffic laws, no sanitation laws, no zoning, etc.) can kinda work. We think that the West should have more Nepali-style buildings with flat roofs for hanging out on, clotheslines, solar water heating, no central heating or AC, etc. These buildings have a smaller environmental impact with minimal impact on comfort (in the right climate, anyway).</li>
<li>We have new confidence that we can figure out food/water safety, public transit, taxis, restaurants, etc. just about anywhere.</li>
<li>We’ve had lots of time to learn about, talk about, and reflect on religions (mostly Buddhism). We’re happy to talk your ear off about it anytime.</li>
<li>We have an alarming amount of Kathmandu dust and pollution in our lungs. In general, our immune systems have been through a lot, possibly for the better.</li>
<li>Seeing suffering people and animals every day strongly reminded us to help others as much as possible.</li>
<li>We have very mixed feelings about future travel. On one hand, we love Oregon and we’ve had enough of the hassles of traveling (not to mention the expense and environmental impact). On the other hand, we find ourselves absentmindedly looking up job openings in Estonia and Singapore.</li>
<li>While still in Nepal, as we were planning our travels to Japan, we expected that we would lightheartedly joke about the cultural transition. Nope, we had a genuinely difficult time adjusting to all the differences! We both caught ourselves nodding sideways (the Nepali way) on several occasions. We felt indignant that we had just gone through all this effort to learn a new language (Nepali), yet we still couldn’t understand the (Japanese) speech of the people around us. It was hard, but it also provided a convenient transition period to minimize culture shock in the States.</li>
<li>We stayed in Nepal for just the right amount of time. We thoroughly enjoyed having enough time to truly settle into Boudha, but Nepal doesn’t feel like home.</li>
<li>Similarly, we studied religion for just the right amount of time. It was really wonderful to be immersed in the monastery school and debate with nuns over lunch. At the same time, it feels good to study technology, math, and science again.</li>
<li>To generalize, we reaffirmed the importance of balance. In the past, we wished for more chances to explore the world and more time to think about topics like religion, philosophy, and anthropology; I missed learning languages. In Nepal, though, we missed family+friends, the coziness of crafting, our musical instruments, and tech+math+science. It’ll be an ongoing challenge to give all of these priorities the attention they deserve.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Our New Living Arrangement</h2>
<p>We really lucked out! Our university’s family housing has a waitlist over a year long and we made it to the top right on time. Additionally, there are a variety of sizes and costs to the units, and you have to take the one that’s available when you finish your wait. We got the perfect size and budget, and our particular unit was remodeled right before we moved in!</p>
<p>So now we have a nice one-bedroom apartment that’s about a 7-minute walk from the edge of campus, on a quiet street, with good internet, and all utilities included. We’re having a good time making the space our own (by cooking a lot of Nepali food, for example).</p>
<p>Unfortunately, Kendrea’s had to spend a lot of time out of the apartment. More on that after the pictures.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/50/img_5096-scaled.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5096-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5096-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5096-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5096-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/50/img_5092-1-8-scaled.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5092-1-8-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5092-1-8-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5092-1-8-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5092-1-8-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/50/img_5091-1-8-scaled.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5091-1-8-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5091-1-8-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5091-1-8-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5091-1-8-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/50/img_5212-scaled.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5212-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5212-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5212-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/50/responsive/img_5212-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<h2>What We’re Up To</h2>
<h4>Gabriel</h4>
<p>I have quite the set of classes compared to what we took in Nepal! I’m taking a full course load of computer science, physics, and (surprisingly) geography. Here’s a brief description of each:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Analysis of Algorithms</strong>: Basically the class so far has been, “here’s an impossible-sounding task. Solve it.” followed by confusion, then ideas, then a solution. Some people complain that this kind of work won’t be useful in industry, but I only really want a job where it would be…</li>
<li><strong>Programming Language Fundamentals</strong>: Programming is telling a computer what to do. There are many different philosophies to accomplish this, and this class talks about the unique challenges in defining and evaluating the grammar and semantics of a language.</li>
<li><strong>Energy Alternatives</strong>: A 7-person physics colloquium about the physical limits of classical and alternative energy sources. We talk about the benefits and drawbacks of coal, natural gas, hydro, wave, geothermal, wind, solar, nuclear, biomass, and many other sources of energy.</li>
<li><strong>The Weird World of Quantum Mechanics</strong>: Another very small physics colloquium about the nature of reality at the smallest testable and verifiable scale. In contrast to most other physics classes, the only inclusion of math is to demonstrate relationships. The class is mostly theory and discussion. The same professor teaches colloquia other terms about the physics and philosophy of time and consciousness.</li>
<li><strong>Geography of International Development and Globalization</strong>: Why are some countries rich and others poor? How have people tried to explain this in the past, and what did they get wrong? This class is about how the expansion of capitalism and colonialism left marks on the globalized world we’re in today. There’s also a lot of discussion of the effects of a growing population and shifting labor market. Each student picks a country to focus on throughout the term, so I picked Eswatini!</li>
</ul>
<p>I’ve been surviving the transition from monastery coursework alright, and I got used to having an apartment right by campus pretty quickly. My proximity has also facilitates extracurriculars like participation in security club.</p>
<p>I’m studying computer science with a focus on computer security. This term, through the security club, I’ve joined a group of six other students to compete in the Pacific Rim Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition, in which you take on the task of running a mock company’s server infrastructure in the face of professional hackers… who are way better at attacking than anyone is at defending. And they’re also scouts from big companies looking to hire. And you have to defend the network for two 8-hour blocks over a weekend. We did well in the qualifiers last week, and everyone is optimistic about our performance in Seattle coming up at the end of March.</p>
<h4>Kendrea</h4>
<p>I’m working at <a href="http://galois.com">Galois</a>! Surprise! Gabriel and I have been excited about Galois for a long time now. I received an internship offer while in Japan; as of February 2, I’ve now finished two weeks of a ten-week internship. It’s a shame that I have to spend 3-5 days a week in Portland so soon after arriving in the States, but it’s worth it to hang out with a concentrated group of ridiculously kind and smart people. My goal is to sneakily convince them that Gabriel, as a fellow ridiculously kind and smart person, belongs there, too. I’ve spent most of my work time so far studying up on functional programming (Scala), abstract algebra (category theory), and epistemology (Quine). I’m working with a philosopher at a tech company named after a mathematician—I love that I usually can’t even tell if I’m doing philosophy, computer science, or math! Just today, I jumped in on a new project to consolidate models in an effort to identify interventions that would alleviate food insecurity in Ethiopia.</p>
<h2>Thank you!</h2>
<p>…for following along, listening to our stories, and supporting us!</p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The halfway point</title>
        <author>
            <name>Arian and Karen</name>
        </author>
        <link href="/the-halfway-point/index.html"/>
        <id>/the-halfway-point/index.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-09T20:20:17-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    It’s strange how the pace of life is notoriously slower here and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>It’s strange how the pace of life is notoriously slower here and yet for us it feels like there’s a mountain of work and never enough hours in the day. Some of that can be attributed to necessary daily rituals such as cooking, washing dishes, hanging laundry out on the line. There’s very little prepackaged convenience foods so meals require more food prep. We are so lucky that we live close to the central shopping area of Mbabane, but it still takes longer to walk to the stores and back than it would to do it by car (not to mention that we have to carry all of those groceries up the hill!). I don’t mind the chores though since they seem like a natural and essential part of the daily life. The more difficult part is the office work. There’s a constant level of frustration because the “right way” of doing things is often completely impractical here. You will have a time sensitive email that needs to be sent ASAP, but the internet is down (or the power is out). Last week we had a flash flood. I couldn’t cross the road to get to a meeting in the building right across the street because the road had turned into white water rapids! Funding is always on the verge of being pulled away from the project and the cut backs are crippling our efforts. There’s never enough hands to make the work light. Despite these challenges, our coworkers are excited about the direction of the project. It may not happen quickly, but progress is being made.</p>
<p>It’s also amazing how long six months can feel. I really can’t focus on the total time remaining because it seems unbearable to be away from family and friends for so long. But, one more day seems manageable. So, I am taking it one day at a time!</p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>January in Eswatini</title>
        <author>
            <name>Arian and Karen</name>
        </author>
        <link href="/january-in-eswatini/index.html"/>
        <id>/january-in-eswatini/index.html</id>

        <updated>2020-01-26T12:06:48-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    One more week left of January. Nothing exciting since our return. We&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>One more week left of January. Nothing exciting since our return. We did get to go on a hike with some other volunteers to the top of Sibebe Rock, also called Execution Rock. It looks like a hill, but is actually the largest rock in the world (depending on who you ask…). It was some beautiful landscape with some trails through fields, grazing cattle, and even a lone horse!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/51/PANO_20200104_062518.vr_-scaled.jpg" alt="I felt a little like we were a fellowship of sorts&amp;#8230;" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_062518.vr_-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_062518.vr_-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_062518.vr_-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_062518.vr_-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>We left way too early in the morning after waking up around 5am. I am not a morning person, so this was not an easy feat! We took a taxi to a starting point and just started walking the nearest path, hoping that it was the right away! We ended up walking through a homestead where we were given friendly help and they removed a section of their fence so we could walk through!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/51/IMG_20200104_063822-scaled.jpg" alt="Such a beautiful valley" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_063822-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_063822-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_063822-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_063822-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>Part of the walk was along a rough road that was crazy narrow and steep in parts. I can’t imagine having to drive it! At one point, we saw some grass bundled together to be used on a thatch roof. It was pretty cool just seeing them lying there drying out. We also walked past a cave/alcove where a horse was hanging out. Unfortunately, I didn’t have my camera ready in time to get a shot of him still in there.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/51/IMG_20200104_081548-scaled.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_081548-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_081548-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_081548-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_081548-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/51/IMG_20200104_065157-scaled.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_065157-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_065157-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_065157-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_065157-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/51/IMG_20200104_094154-scaled.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_094154-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_094154-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_094154-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_094154-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>The hike ended up being several hours and was pretty tiring overall. Having started earlier, it wasn’t too hot until toward the end. I don’t think we could have done it much later!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/51/PANO_20200104_070208.vr_-scaled.jpg" alt="Rolling hills all over" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_070208.vr_-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_070208.vr_-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_070208.vr_-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_070208.vr_-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>We also walked past people working in their fields of corn and other crops. The area is on the outer edges of Mbabane so much more rural than we see day-to-day. It was so nice getting away for a few hours.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/51/PANO_20200104_082426.vr_-scaled.jpg" alt="Sitting on a lower part of Sibebe Rock looking down" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_082426.vr_-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_082426.vr_-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_082426.vr_-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/PANO_20200104_082426.vr_-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>That’s really the only cool thing we’ve done this month, but hopefully there will be more! The hot season is apparently going to be cooling off in the near future which will make it easier to enjoy the outdoors, at least until it gets cold! We still have several game preserves to go to that we can’t miss!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/51/IMG_20200104_085241-scaled.jpg" alt="Looking across from Sibebe Rock. We&amp;#8217;re at the highest point" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_085241-scaled-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_085241-scaled-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_085241-scaled-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/51/responsive/IMG_20200104_085241-scaled-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>I’m grateful that we have a great group of fellow volunteers who enjoy doing fun things! Trying to find our way around can be daunting, so it’s nice to be able to go with volunteers who have knowledge of a place or better understanding of how to go places. Since we can’t drive (Peace Corps Eswatini rule), we generally know the area where we live. Having a larger group makes these fun adventures possible!</p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Tokyo</title>
        <author>
            <name>Damian and Lilly</name>
        </author>
        <link href="/tokyo-2/index.html"/>
        <id>/tokyo-2/index.html</id>

        <updated>2020-01-05T14:03:37-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    As some of you may already know from other blog posts, we&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>As some of you may already know from other blog posts, we had my entire immediate family come visit us in Japan for Christmas! My parents wanted to spend some time in Japan being a tourist on their way out to meet up with us (they arrived 5 days before Gabriel and Kendrea) so they looked into various attractions in Narita (where they landed), Tokyo (where they could catch a train to Sendai), and other places along the way. In their research, they found a site claiming that the Emperors palace is open on December 23rd due to it being the Emperors birthday. Since the palace is pretty much always closed to the public, Lilly and I thought that sounded really neat and wanted to go see the palace as well.</p>
<p>In preparation for the trip, Lilly found a good AirBNB house that was a bit on the outskirts of Tokyo but still had train access. This allowed us to have easy access to Tokyo without needing to pay tons of money to actually be in Tokyo. The house was two stories and had two bedrooms, pretty much a perfect match for our needs!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/airBNB-house-outside.jpg" alt="Outside of the AirBNB house, we had the whole thing to ourselves." sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/airBNB-house-outside-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/airBNB-house-outside-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/airBNB-house-outside-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/airBNB-house-outside-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<h2>Saturday</h2>
<p>For those that aren’t aware, our apartment in Tome is about 5 hours north of Tokyo by car, and there are tolls along the way that add up to almost $100! That said, it’s still cheaper than buying two Shinkansen ( 新幹線 : bullet train) tickets as those are over $100 per person. It is a pretty drive though, with lots of mountains along the way. Though we didn’t get to appreciate the views very much as we left around 5am in an attempt to get to Tokyo around 10 am alternated sleeping in the car.</p>
<p>Traffic didn’t quite play along nicely as we got into Tokyo, and we had to stop and get gas, so it ended up being closer to 11 am by the time we made it to the house. From there, Lilly and I left the car parked in the lot at the house and took the train to Tokyo Station to meet up with my parents. We didn’t quite time things right with them and ended up waiting at the station for a bit before my parents arrived, but they did finally make it.</p>
<p>For dinner that night we went to yakiniku ( 焼肉 : grilled meat) which is similar to Korean BBQ in the States, except that they don’t use Korean spices or cuts of meat. One of the favorites was gyūtan (牛タン : cow tongue) which has almost no fat, marbled or otherwise, unlike most cuts of meat in Japan.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/Yakinikuwiki.jpg" alt="Traditional grills have live coals under a wire grill and people use metal tongs to grill the food" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/Yakinikuwiki-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Yakinikuwiki-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Yakinikuwiki-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Yakinikuwiki-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/Gyutan_teishoku.jpg" alt="Gyūtan with the usual cuts to make the meat a little more edible. Yakiniku gyūtan is usually cut pretty thin to allow it cook faster, though we&amp;#8217;ve gotten it thick like this at places before" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/Gyutan_teishoku-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Gyutan_teishoku-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Gyutan_teishoku-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Gyutan_teishoku-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<h2>Sunday</h2>
<p>For Sunday, we went to Nikorai-do ( 復活大聖堂 or ニコライ堂 : Holy Resurrection Cathedral or Nikolai’s House). The cathedral is the seat of Metropolitan Daniel of the Japanese Orthodox Church, though he was actually at the hospital that day and we didn’t get to see him. As such, it wasn’t a hierarchical service, but it was still very nice and the choir was very good!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/Holy_Resurrection_Cathedral_in_Tokyo.jpg" alt="View as you walk up to the cathedral. It used to be on a hill overlooking the city, but then the city came up and engulfed the church." sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/Holy_Resurrection_Cathedral_in_Tokyo-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Holy_Resurrection_Cathedral_in_Tokyo-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Holy_Resurrection_Cathedral_in_Tokyo-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Holy_Resurrection_Cathedral_in_Tokyo-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/holy-resurrection-cathedral.jpg" alt="Iconostasis inside. The choir stands off on the right, and confessions happen on the left before the service starts. Also, the reliquary at the edge on the right side of the picture has a relic of St. Nicholas of Japan for people to venerate." sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/holy-resurrection-cathedral-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/holy-resurrection-cathedral-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/holy-resurrection-cathedral-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/holy-resurrection-cathedral-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>They were very welcoming at the church and even provided us with a sheet of paper that had the epistle and gospel reading in English! There’s also a deacon from America that serves at the cathedral and he did a litany in English. We were less fortunate with the priests giving confession, but they knew enough to ask our names, verify we were orthodox, and give a blessing.</p>
<p>Lilly and I would like to go back to Nikorai-do at some point for a service with the Metropolitan serving, but that will have to be another trip.</p>
<p>After the service we found some breakfast that didn’t have gluten and then walked around the part of Tokyo that the church is in, as well as took a trip down the train line a bit to see more.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/sunday-walking.jpg" alt="Selfie overlooking a channel as we were walking to Akihabara" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/sunday-walking-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/sunday-walking-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/sunday-walking-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/sunday-walking-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>The first place we went was Akihabara (秋葉原) as it’s within walking distance from the church. Though known for a few things, we were mostly interested in the electronics part. We found a few hole-in-the-wall type shops, one of which ended up being a super packed little mall (complete with escalators) with tons of different types of shops inside. A lot of the shops were closed since it was Sunday, but we did get to see some fun and interesting stuff!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/akihabara-neo-geo.jpg" alt="A free Neo-Geo (no coins required) tucked away in a small shop in Akihabara" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/akihabara-neo-geo-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/akihabara-neo-geo-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/akihabara-neo-geo-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/akihabara-neo-geo-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>After spending some time poking around shops, we went to the Edo-Tokyo Museum to see some history for the area. The museum covers from 1590 through 1964 showing everything from models of the city layout; to artifacts like clothing, pottery, and buildings; to old electronics; to school lunches through the years. We thought the museum was really cool, so here’s a bunch of photos!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/edo-museum-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/edo-museum-2.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-2-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-2-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-2-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-2-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/edo-museum-5.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-5-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-5-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-5-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-5-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/edo-museum-3.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-3-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-3-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-3-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-3-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/edo-museum-4.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-4-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-4-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-4-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-4-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/edo-museum-6.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-6-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-6-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-6-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-6-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/edo-museum-7.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-7-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-7-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-7-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/edo-museum-7-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>The final part of our Sunday was a trip to Sensō-ji temple (金龍山浅草寺) and the impressive Kaminarimon Gate (雷門) leading up to the temple. The area directly behind the gate has a whole bunch of shops (though we apparently didn’t get any pictures of that part), and after them another gate, followed by shops selling stuff more closely related to the temple, and finally the temple itself. Buddhist temples have lots of gold in the inside, though people don’t really go into the temples and shrines in Japan except for ceremonies.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/Kaminarimon-across-the-street.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/Kaminarimon-across-the-street-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Kaminarimon-across-the-street-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Kaminarimon-across-the-street-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Kaminarimon-across-the-street-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/kaminarimon.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/kaminarimon-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/kaminarimon-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/kaminarimon-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/kaminarimon-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/three-americans-under-the-lamp.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/three-americans-under-the-lamp-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/three-americans-under-the-lamp-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/three-americans-under-the-lamp-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/three-americans-under-the-lamp-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/garden-Buddha.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/garden-Buddha-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/garden-Buddha-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/garden-Buddha-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/garden-Buddha-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/another-gate.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/another-gate-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/another-gate-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/another-gate-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/another-gate-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/senso-ji-temple-shops.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/senso-ji-temple-shops-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/senso-ji-temple-shops-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/senso-ji-temple-shops-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/senso-ji-temple-shops-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/senso-ji-temple-pagoda.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/senso-ji-temple-pagoda-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/senso-ji-temple-pagoda-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/senso-ji-temple-pagoda-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/senso-ji-temple-pagoda-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/second-gate.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/second-gate-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/second-gate-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/second-gate-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/second-gate-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/inside-the-temple.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/inside-the-temple-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/inside-the-temple-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/inside-the-temple-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/inside-the-temple-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>We ended our day getting dinner at a nearby restaurant and got to introduce a few more interesting Japanese dishes as well as absorb more cigarette smoke than I think I have in my entire life up until now combined.</p>
<h2>Monday</h2>
<p>Monday was supposed to be our day to visit the Emperor’s Palace, but apparently that wasn’t to be. Since the old Emperor abdicated this year, his son ascended the throne and the new day is some time in February…. Not exactly compatible with our plans for the day! So since our original plans were foiled, we had to find some other things to fill the day with.</p>
<p>Our first thought was to go to Ueno Park (上野公園) and visit either the zoo or the one of the museums there, but apparently lots of things that stay open on the weekend choose Monday to be their day off. So pretty much everything in Ueno Park was closed. The only thing in the park that we could see was the shrine, so we poked our heads in and took a quick look around.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/ueno-shrine.jpg" alt="This building at the Ueno Park shrine has clearly had a new copper roof put on. Nice and shiny!" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/ueno-shrine-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/ueno-shrine-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/ueno-shrine-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/ueno-shrine-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>After Ueno Park, we hopped back on the train and took a trip to the old black market district Ameya-Yokochō (アメヤ横丁). This was pretty much the only open air market we’ve seen like it in Japan thus far. There were lots of seafood stalls, meat stalls, some stalls selling trinkets and American-style goods, and some restaurants.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/ameya-yokocho.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/ameya-yokocho-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/ameya-yokocho-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/ameya-yokocho-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/ameya-yokocho-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/grilled-and-smoked-meat-stall.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/grilled-and-smoked-meat-stall-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/grilled-and-smoked-meat-stall-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/grilled-and-smoked-meat-stall-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/grilled-and-smoked-meat-stall-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/sea-food-stall.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/sea-food-stall-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/sea-food-stall-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/sea-food-stall-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/sea-food-stall-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/another-seafood-stall.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/another-seafood-stall-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/another-seafood-stall-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/another-seafood-stall-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/another-seafood-stall-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>From there we took a train down to the Tokyo Skytree (東京スカイツリ) which is the tallest tower, and the second largest structure in the world (according the Wikipedia anyway). In the basement of the train station there, we saw a very cool candy making shop that had someone making candy as people watched. We then went upstairs and found lunch at some food carts at the base of the tower. They even had some gluten free food which was good!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/Tokyo_Skytree.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/Tokyo_Skytree-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Tokyo_Skytree-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Tokyo_Skytree-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/Tokyo_Skytree-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/candy-maker.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/candy-maker-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/candy-maker-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/candy-maker-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/candy-maker-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/finished-candy.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/finished-candy-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/finished-candy-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/finished-candy-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/finished-candy-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/hard-candy.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/hard-candy-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/hard-candy-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/hard-candy-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/hard-candy-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>After that we started our long trip home, but we did stop briefly along the way at Kawagoe (川越市), specifically Koedo (小江戸) which means “Little Edo” as it’s the only surviving section of Edo period Tokyo. The houses and shops all date back to the 1600’s or earlier! We didn’t get to look around that much as it was late and most everything was closed, but we did get to see some really neat old buildings and we did stop at an open shop to look around a bit!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/61/45914575071_bf2b4cbc0c_b.jpg" alt="Koedo at night, lots of old wooden buildings!" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/61/responsive/45914575071_bf2b4cbc0c_b-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/45914575071_bf2b4cbc0c_b-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/45914575071_bf2b4cbc0c_b-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/61/responsive/45914575071_bf2b4cbc0c_b-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Sorry this was a long post, we packed a lot into those three days! It was the longest trip Lilly and I have taken from home and we definitely trust our little “Kei” car much more now that’s it’s proven that it can make long trips. We’re definitely going to have more road trips as we explore more of Japan!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Family Christmas in Japan</title>
        <author>
            <name>Damian and Lilly</name>
        </author>
        <link href="/family-christmas-in-japan/index.html"/>
        <id>/family-christmas-in-japan/index.html</id>

        <updated>2020-01-03T09:31:46-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The last two weeks of December ended up being our first leave&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The last two weeks of December ended up being our first leave from Peace Corps. From the start, we wanted to visit Gabriel and Kendrea in Nepal, and Damian and Lilly in Japan. Unfortunately, it’s hard to get much leave in the first few months, plus the cost was horrendous, so we didn’t end up going to Nepal. Instead, we went to Japan with a bonus: Gabriel and Kendrea finished their study abroad and were going through Japan on their way home to Oregon! We were there for two weeks and stayed at Damian and Lilly’s apartment in Sanuma (in Tome).</p>
<p>We took a shuttle bus to Johannesburg so we could fly out of O.R. Tambo International Airport, then had a layover in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. We even made a quick stop in Seoul, Korea for reasons I still don’t understand, but necessitated everyone leaving, going through security screening again, then re-boarding. Definitely wasn’t some emergency thing since we did it both ways.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191220_193327.jpg" alt="We made it!" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191220_193327-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191220_193327-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191220_193327-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191220_193327-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>We landed in Narita and took a train to a guesthouse for the night. It was a great little place very close to a historic street. In the morning, we walked down the street, and got fire-roasted yams and chestnuts from different street vendors. We talked to Karen’s brother Dan and he highly recommended that we go to a close by temple complex, so we headed over there. It was quite beautiful and I’m glad we could go.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191221_121614.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_121614-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_121614-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_121614-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_121614-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191221_122558.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_122558-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_122558-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_122558-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_122558-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191221_122811.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_122811-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_122811-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_122811-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191221_122811-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>Getting back to the guesthouse, we met a guy named Ignacio who was from Belgium and was finishing up a year-long bike ride around the world! We chatted for a bit and got insanely jealous. He’s been to so many places and gotten to see so much. Places I wouldn’t normally think of as safe enough to visit, let alone to cycle through! You can read more about him on <a href="https://nacho-on-a-bike.com/">his blog</a>.</p>
<p>Damian and Lilly met up with us in Tokyo and we spent two nights there. Tokyo is a great city! So many things to see. We took the train wherever we went (public transit can be so liberating!) and went to several areas. We also spent a number of hours at the <a href="https://www.edo-tokyo-museum.or.jp/en/about/">Edo Museum</a>. So many great exhibits showcasing the Edo period. I love miniature models/dioramas, and this place had so many!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191222_151059.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_151059-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_151059-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_151059-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_151059-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191222_151411-rotated-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_151411-rotated-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_151411-rotated-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_151411-rotated-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_151411-rotated-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191222_155608.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_155608-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_155608-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_155608-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_155608-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191222_160527.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_160527-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_160527-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_160527-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_160527-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>We also went to the St. Nicholas cathedral (ok, so it’s actually called <a href="https://en.japantravel.com/tokyo/nikolai-do-orthodox-cathedral/5435">Holy Resurrection Cathedral</a>) and were able to attend liturgy. It was so wonderful since there’s no Orthodox church in Eswatini. I couldn’t understand it, but I was able to follow along in an English-language book and sing along phonetically. Saint Nicholas and the cathedral are actually pretty big deals in Tokyo. Since there are so few Christians, the bells are a bit unusual and well-known. The Edo Museum even had a recording of the bells to accompany their model!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191222_094300.jpg" alt="Locally referred to as Nikolaido-do (Home of Nicholas)" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_094300-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_094300-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_094300-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191222_094300-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>We went up to Damian and Lilly’s place and got settled in. The next day, we drove to Sendai Station (not as far as Tokyo) to pickup Gabriel and Kendrea. Now our group was the full six. It was such a wonderful feeling being around all of them after so long! That’s definitely the hardest part of being so far away.</p>
<p>During the visit, we played games, talked, and saw various sites in the region. We were consistently amazed with the number of vending machines out and about! Pretty much every block, you’d see one, two, six different machines. Mostly beverages, but it was very cool to see machines where the cans of hot drinks were actually hot! Coffee, cocoa, corn soup, all ready to go. It’s hard to imagine how they get enough business.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191229_160913.jpg" alt="Hot? Cold? They got you covered!" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_160913-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_160913-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_160913-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_160913-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>In case you couldn’t get enough from the machines, there were convenience stores (<em>kombini</em>s) every few blocks. One chain called Lawson, and then quite a few 7-11’s. Food was readily available and reasonably priced. The only real issues were reading the labels, and my stupid celiac gut. It turns out that the Japanese <em>really</em> love their soy sauce. No, I mean <em>really</em>. It was hard to find almost anything prepared that was safe. Thankfully, Lilly was able to check the ingredient lists, and I was also able to use my phone to translate. It was definitely disappointing to be restricted like that. We were fine buying our own supplies and cooking back at the apartment though.</p>
<p>During our stay we saw a number of different temples. They’re quite beautiful. We also saw a windmill! It was a gift from the Dutch and installed at Naganuma Futopia Park. They also had a <em>very</em> long slide with rollers for the surface. It was probably for kids, but it didn’t stop all of us from having great fun on it too!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191229_150214-rotated-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_150214-rotated-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_150214-rotated-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_150214-rotated-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_150214-rotated-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191229_145129.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_145129-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_145129-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_145129-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_145129-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191229_145339.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_145339-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_145339-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_145339-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191229_145339-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>Before we left, we saw the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toyoma_Education_Museum">Toyoma Education Museum</a> in Tome which portrays a typical Japanese elementary school in the late 1800’s with lots of interesting exhibits in former classrooms. The next morning, on our way to the station, we visited the town of Ishinomaki. This was a town very heavily hit during the tsunami a few years ago, losing many children and other people in the flooding. It was sad to see how much recovery there still was left, though it was clear there was also incredible progress.</p>
<p>Our last stop was in the touristy town of Matsushima. It was a beautiful place with ocean views and a gorgeous park. Due to the features of their bay, they were somewhat protected during the tsunami and sustained less damage.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191231_135854.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_135854-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_135854-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_135854-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_135854-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191231_135928.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_135928-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_135928-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_135928-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_135928-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191231_140005.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_140005-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_140005-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_140005-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_140005-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191231_140059.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_140059-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_140059-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_140059-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_140059-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>With some difficulty, we said our good-byes at the station. It’s never easy. Kendrea was to have an internship interview the next morning, and she and Gabriel would be getting ready for their own departure back to the US. We took the <a href="https://www.japan-guide.com/e/e2018.html">Shinkansen</a> (bullet train) to Tokyo. It went as fast as 140mph! Definitely a great way to travel, though the price was outrageous…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/47/IMG_20191231_152011.jpg" alt="Leaving the station (don&amp;#8217;t worry, not ours!)" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_152011-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_152011-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_152011-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/47/responsive/IMG_20191231_152011-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>Now back home in Eswatini, safe and sound (and Gabriel/Kendrea also home, for real), it’s time to settle back in and get back to work. I’m so glad we were able to make the trip, but it was a difficult departure. We already can’t wait to see them all again!</p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>December in Eswatini</title>
        <author>
            <name>Arian and Karen</name>
        </author>
        <link href="/december-in-eswatini/index.html"/>
        <id>/december-in-eswatini/index.html</id>

        <updated>2019-12-28T11:33:16-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    It seemed strange to be preparing for Christmas with the sun shining&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>It seemed strange to be preparing for Christmas with the sun shining so warmly.  To help get into the holiday spirit, Arian joined a small singing group.  They lead Christmas caroling at a community center in town.  The kids joined right in and a good time was had by all.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/46/IMG_20191217_173351.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191217_173351-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191217_173351-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191217_173351-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191217_173351-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/46/IMG_20191217_183050.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191217_183050-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191217_183050-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191217_183050-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191217_183050-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>We also had the opportunity to attend a youth Christmas concert.  The event was organized by a Taiwanese program that provides musical instruction to high-risk youth.  They teach the children traditional Swazi dance, western choral music, and orchestral instruments.   At the same time, they provide apprenticeships for local musicans who are interested in learning to be instructors.  It was a lot of fun to see how much the program has accomplished in only two years!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/46/IMG_20191208_162837.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_162837-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_162837-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_162837-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_162837-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/46/IMG_20191208_151226.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_151226-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_151226-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_151226-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_151226-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/46/IMG_20191208_154234.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_154234-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_154234-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_154234-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191208_154234-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>The most exciting thing about December was knowing that we would soon be seeing Damian, Lilly, Gabriel, and Kendrea in Japan! We will be with them for two weeks. Definitely makes the year easier!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/46/IMG_20191219_083022.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191219_083022-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191219_083022-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191219_083022-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191219_083022-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/46/IMG_20191219_210352.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191219_210352-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191219_210352-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191219_210352-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191219_210352-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/46/IMG_20191220_155824.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_155824-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_155824-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_155824-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_155824-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/46/IMG_20191220_174810.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_174810-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_174810-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_174810-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_174810-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/46/IMG_20191220_194126-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_194126-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_194126-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_194126-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/46/responsive/IMG_20191220_194126-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Busy roadsides</title>
        <author>
            <name>Arian and Karen</name>
        </author>
        <link href="/busy-roadsides/index.html"/>
        <id>/busy-roadsides/index.html</id>

        <updated>2019-12-28T08:40:41-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I thought I’d use this post to talk about something interesting I’ve&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I thought I’d use this post to talk about something interesting I’ve noticed here. The country is relatively poor, with most people making less than $1 USD/day, but there is no end to the entrepreneurial spirit. Pretty much every roadside is dotted with various vendor stalls. Stands with roasted corn, fruit, salty snacks, and grilled meats to eat, buckets and water tanks, and the ever-present MTN data/airtime cards can be found all over the place. Other stands offer car washes, haircuts, or cell phone repair. Most of the stands are built out of poles (4-5″ diameter), pallets, or corrugated metal, or just the back of a truck.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/42/IMG_20191207_121005-scaled-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121005-scaled-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121005-scaled-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121005-scaled-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121005-scaled-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/42/IMG_20191207_120716-scaled-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_120716-scaled-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_120716-scaled-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_120716-scaled-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_120716-scaled-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/42/IMG_20191207_120607-scaled-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_120607-scaled-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_120607-scaled-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_120607-scaled-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_120607-scaled-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/42/IMG_20191207_121007-scaled-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121007-scaled-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121007-scaled-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121007-scaled-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121007-scaled-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/42/IMG_20191207_121028-scaled-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121028-scaled-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121028-scaled-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121028-scaled-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191207_121028-scaled-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/42/IMG_20191127_151631-scaled-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191127_151631-scaled-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191127_151631-scaled-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191127_151631-scaled-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191127_151631-scaled-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/42/IMG_20191127_145623-scaled-1.jpg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191127_145623-scaled-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191127_145623-scaled-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191127_145623-scaled-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/IMG_20191127_145623-scaled-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>It’s super cool to see the many ways people find to make money. Crime is relatively low, despite the poverty, and instead lots of individual businesses abound. Even at work, it seems many people have a side hustle. Pay is low, even for professional jobs, so they are always on the lookout for opportunities.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/42/PANO_20191207_112341.vr_-scaled-1.jpg" alt="A market within the Mbabane bus rank" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/42/responsive/PANO_20191207_112341.vr_-scaled-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/PANO_20191207_112341.vr_-scaled-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/PANO_20191207_112341.vr_-scaled-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/42/responsive/PANO_20191207_112341.vr_-scaled-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>The variety of items for sale includes clothing, shoes, soap, jewelry, hats, and much more. I’d love to publish more pictures, but it’s kind of hard to get images without asking lots of people for permission! I try to be sneaky and get shots when people are facing away, but that’s not always an option. If I can get more in the future, I’d love to post more!</p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Goodbye Nepal</title>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriel and Kendrea</name>
        </author>
        <link href="/goodbye-nepal/index.html"/>
        <id>/goodbye-nepal/index.html</id>

        <updated>2019-12-26T10:53:20-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Greetings from 1:00 in the morning, somewhere over southeast Asia! Time to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Greetings from 1:00 in the morning, somewhere over southeast Asia!</p>
<p>Time to catch you up on our final three weeks in Nepal.</p>
<p>We went on lots of little errands to prepare to leave. We enjoyed finding new parts of town. Gabriel really likes the traditional architecture, so here’s a representative door.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/IMG_4876.jpeg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4876-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4876-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4876-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4876-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>We don’t usually drink coffee, but we enjoyed studying at the Western-style coffee shop and expanding our coffee horizons. We sometimes even got the coveted stupa-view seats by the windows.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/IMG_4887.jpeg" alt="Himalayan Java Coffee is a chain that was founded in Nepal. They&amp;#8217;ve even expanded to the US now." sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4887-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4887-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4887-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4887-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>It turns out that Nepal has a holiday for eating grapefruit, so instead of our usual one-on-one language partner class, all the Nepali language partners cooked up a grapefruit dish for all of the students! It was a truly bizarre concoction, with grapefruit, milk (we had a special milk-free version), peanuts, chillies, mustard oil, sugar, sesame seeds, spices, and who knows what all else. We sat around in a circle on the stage at the monastery cafe to eat it. </p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/IMG_4851.jpeg" alt="We were told that the grapefruit peels should go on our heads, but I am highly suspicious about this&amp;#8211;only the foreigners wore grapefruit hats!" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4851-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4851-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4851-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4851-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/IMG_4855.jpeg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4855-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4855-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4855-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4855-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>Our host family had some shelves installed, so of course they called up the shelf bike dude.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/65ffd467-76e7-4006-8fed-c68e74b2338f.jpeg" alt="What, how else would you transport your furniture?" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/65ffd467-76e7-4006-8fed-c68e74b2338f-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/65ffd467-76e7-4006-8fed-c68e74b2338f-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/65ffd467-76e7-4006-8fed-c68e74b2338f-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/65ffd467-76e7-4006-8fed-c68e74b2338f-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>We sang in the Boudha Community Chorale Christmas concert! It turned out to be quite the fancy affair. It took place at the monastery cafe, so we enjoyed a feast of fusion food afterward. It didn’t start out very auspiciously from our perspective–we took an accidental midday nap that made us late and then two people had to help get Gabriel’s tie on–but the singing part went well! The Boudha Community Chorale (mostly foreigners) hosted the concert; the British Model College Choir (all Nepali students) and the Kathmandu String Ensemble (all Nepali adults) also performed. The musical quality wasn’t up to the standards we’re used to in Corvallis, but it was still a pretty special experience to sing the Hallelujah Chorus at the top of our lungs with a large, diverse musical ensemble at a beautifully lit Buddhist outdoor cafe in Kathmandu.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/DSC08795.jpeg" alt="Boudha Community Chorale" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/DSC08795-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/DSC08795-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/DSC08795-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/DSC08795-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/DSC08844.jpeg" alt="All set up at Utpala Cafe" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/DSC08844-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/DSC08844-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/DSC08844-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/DSC08844-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>Swing club wrapped up very well! Seven people, including us, participated in the final lesson. We taught our most advanced students tandem Charleston while Yuki gave beginner lessons to some newer folks. We danced, sang, and laughed to a playlist of holiday swing music.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/IMG_4912.jpeg" alt="We don&amp;#8217;t have any more photos of swing club, so here&amp;#8217;s Mouthy Girl." sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4912-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4912-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4912-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4912-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>We finished finals!! We worked really hard, and we think it paid off (no real-time grading like we’re used to back home, so we’ll need to wait for final grades to come in). I began this semester assuming that I could use my pre-existing philosophy essay skills, but I finally accepted that this school requires a different frame of mind. For my final paper, instead of bringing in my own science-y perspective like I would for philosophy papers at OSU, I tried sticking very closely to traditional Tibetan sources (translated to English, of course). I enjoyed stretching myself in this way, and I think it’s more in line with what the instructors intended. Don’t think that we had too much fun, though. They were still finals. Much stress.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/IMG_4917-1.jpeg" alt="Look at those sources. Am I a real scholar now?" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4917-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4917-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4917-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4917-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>The weather has been warm and sunny. Here’s Yuki demonstrating that one can comfortably snuggle with dogs outside.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/IMG_4930-1.jpeg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4930-1-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4930-1-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4930-1-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4930-1-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>Our last few days in Nepal were pretty pleasant, too. The Himalayas came out to greet us on a clear day. We delivered thank-you notes, recycled lots of class papers, did last-minute shopping around the stupa, had a serendipitous dinner with our friend Tia, and even visited Chökyi Nyima Rinpoche. We listened as he had conversations with other visitors in Tibetan and Nepali. We only spoke with him briefly, but it was lovely to bask in his kind glow.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/media/posts/49/IMG_4943.jpeg" alt="" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4943-xs.webp 300w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4943-sm.webp 480w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4943-md.webp 768w ,/media/posts/49/responsive/IMG_4943-lg.webp 1024w"></p>
<p>See you in Japan!</p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
