
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
    <title>Kulp Family Travels</title>
    <description>A journal of Kulp adventures</description>
    <link>/sites/family/</link>
    <atom:link href="/sites/family/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:57:04 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:57:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Pico</generator>
          <item>
        <title>さようなら！Sayonara!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, and goodbye for now! Today Damian and I get on a plane to Narita airport in Tokyo, where I’ll be oriented for three days before we are sent on our way to Tome on the shinkansen (新幹線), or bullet train! We’ll be leaving PDX at 11:45 AM Oregon time, and arriving in Japan at 2:00 pm their time on Sunday! So we’re losing Saturday afternoon and Sunday morning, nearly a whole day, in crossing the international dateline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who are curious, Japan is 16 hours ahead of the Northwest, which means we’ll frequently be in tomorrow when you’re in today. WooOoOOoo, time travel!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re very excited, and we will probably be very busy, but we’ll be sure to keep everyone updated to the best of our ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/wp-15648456463421257316557351500763.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 10:27:56 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/%25e3%2581%2595%25e3%2582%2588%25e3%2581%2586%25e3%2581%25aa%25e3%2582%2589%25ef%25bc%2581sayonara</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/%25e3%2581%2595%25e3%2582%2588%25e3%2581%2586%25e3%2581%25aa%25e3%2582%2589%25ef%25bc%2581sayonara</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>About Arian &amp;amp; Karen</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Arian and Karen are living in eSwatini (formerly Swaziland) for a year as part of a Peace Corps Response project with the Ministry of Health to develop their electronic medical records (EMR/EHR) system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be pointed out that everything they say is their own and not, in any way, endorsed by the Peace Corps or US Government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our son Damian and his wife Lilly will be living in Tome, Japan for a year with the Japanese Exchange and Teaching (JET) program with Lilly teaching in some local schools while Damian continues with his current job as a remote worker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our son Gabriel and his wife Kendrea spent a semester abroad (August – December) in Nepal near Boudhanath, on the outskirts of Kathmandu, where classes were held at a Tibetan Buddhist monastery. They have since returned home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/07/67468603_10213818049185721_2912186477515374592_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See just &lt;a href=&quot;search?q=africa&quot;&gt;Arian and Karen’s posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:57:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/about-arian-karen</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/about-arian-karen</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>About Damian &amp;amp; Lilly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Damian and Lilly finished their degrees at Oregon State University, got married, and are heading to Japan; it’s been a busy year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilly was accepted into the Japanese Exchange and Teaching (JET) program and placed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tome,_Miyagi&quot;&gt;Tome, Japan&lt;/a&gt;. She’ll be primarily teaching elementary schoolers at Minamikata Elementary School, though she’ll make weekly and monthly trips to 2 other elementary schools and 2 kindergartens for a total of 5 schools. Lilly is the first full time JET Assistant Language Teacher (ALT) that Minamikata Elementary has had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damian is continuing to work for Citycounty Insurance Services (CIS).  The time difference means that he has to wake up really early to have 4 hours of overlap with Oregon.  Since CIS is for Oregon cities and counties, they were a little unsure of having a remote worker from Japan but it’s been working out so far!  Damian also didn’t have any Japanese skills upon first arriving.  He has to spend a lot of time learning the various written languages used here as well as trying to learn the culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be in Tome for a full year, returning around mid-late August 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to come visit us if you want!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:57:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/about-damian-lilly</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/about-damian-lilly</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>About Gabriel &amp;amp; Kendrea</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Biography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello! We’re Kendrea and Gabriel Kulp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kendrea is a third-year student at Oregon State University majoring in Computer Science and Philosophy and minoring in Mathematics; she’s interested in computer ethics and Effective Altruism. Gabriel is a fourth-year student at OSU majoring in Computer Science and minoring in Mathematics and Physics; he’s interested in computer security and its relationship with civil liberties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We enjoy singing, playing musical instruments, messing around with computers, unicycling, interacting with various living creatures, and taking naps. We got married in July 2019, almost exactly a month before leaving for Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/Hires-709-ZF-9924-29976-1-001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unicycling while getting married&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Glossary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/iu-2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Nepal &amp;amp;#8211; an Asian country bordering India and Tibet&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Places&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boudhanath (Boudha) – &lt;/strong&gt;The Tibetan district of Kathmandu. Home of our host family and many monasteries, including Ka-Nying Shedrub Ling. Famous for the Boudhanath Stupa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Himalayas –&lt;/strong&gt; The mountains that form the north border of Nepal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shedrub.org/&quot;&gt;Ka-Nying Shedrub Ling&lt;/a&gt; –&lt;/strong&gt; The monastery that hosts RYI. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kathmandu –&lt;/strong&gt; The capital city of Nepal. The elevation is a bit lower than that of Denver, CO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://oregonstate.edu&quot;&gt;Oregon State University&lt;/a&gt; (OSU) – &lt;/strong&gt;Our home university.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ryi.org/&quot;&gt;Rangjung Yeshe Institute&lt;/a&gt; (RYI) –&lt;/strong&gt; The international school that operates within the monastery. RYI is associated with Kathmandu University, which provides credit for our classes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tibet – &lt;/strong&gt;A mountainous region in western China, separated from Nepal by the Himalayas. The Chinese government suppresses the traditional Buddhist, nomadic culture, so many Tibetans have moved elsewhere — many to Nepal — to practice their lifestyle in peace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Teachers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shedrub.org/about-us/&quot;&gt;Chökyi Nyima Rinpoche&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;/strong&gt;The spiritual head of Ka-Nying Shedrub Ling. “World-renowned teacher and meditation master in the Kagyü and Nyingma traditions of Tibetan Buddhism.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thelostyak.com/&quot;&gt;Geoff Barstow&lt;/a&gt; (Dr. Barstow)&lt;/strong&gt; – The Oregon State University professor who organizes this study abroad. He studies vegetarianism in Tibetan Buddhism. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fr. Greg Sharkey – &lt;/strong&gt;A Catholic priest, professor, and our academic advisor. He is also a key part of our safety net, keeping tabs on everyone and reporting potential issues to Dr. Barstow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Fellow OSU Exchange Students&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jesus&lt;/strong&gt; – A cohort member.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kalie –&lt;/strong&gt; A temporary cohort member.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mesa –&lt;/strong&gt; A cohort member.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yi-Hsiang – &lt;/strong&gt;A cohort member.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yuki – &lt;/strong&gt;A cohort member.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Host Family (in family tree order)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ranju (“Aamaa”) &lt;/strong&gt;— Grandma and head of the household; retired Nepali language teacher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roshan&lt;/strong&gt; — Ranju’s son; works at a bank during the night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Puja &lt;/strong&gt;— Roshan’s wife; lives in a different house with her mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pragoon&lt;/strong&gt; — Roshan and Puja’s 12-year-old son; lives at Puja’s house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Milan &lt;/strong&gt;— Ranju’s son; high-profile investment banker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yikes-we-don’t-know&lt;/strong&gt; — Milan’s wife; I think she also has a high-powered bank job; doesn’t interact with us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ishan&lt;/strong&gt; — Milan and Yikes-we-don’t-know’s 11-year-old son.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saili — &lt;/strong&gt;Ranju’s full-time helper; cooks, does laundry, cleans, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laxmi — &lt;/strong&gt;Ranju’s part-time helper; cooks, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Religious Terms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brahmin — &lt;/strong&gt;The “priestly” caste; the highest social level in Hinduism, which requires special care to maintain ritual purity; the caste of our host family and their servants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/Buddhism&quot;&gt;Buddhism&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;/strong&gt;A minority religion in Nepal, and the main object of our focus for this trip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/Hinduism&quot;&gt;Hinduism&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;/strong&gt;The majority religion in Nepal and India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/lama&quot;&gt;Lama&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;/strong&gt;A Tibetan Buddhist spiritual leader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Khenpo&quot;&gt;Khenpo/Khenmo&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;/strong&gt;Someone who has earned the Tibetan Buddhist equivalent of a doctorate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/stupa&quot;&gt;Stupa&lt;/a&gt; –&lt;/strong&gt; A Buddhist landmark for worship. Boudhanath has the largest stupa in Nepal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/Tibetan-Buddhism&quot;&gt;Tibetan Buddhism&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;/strong&gt;A type of &lt;a href=&quot;https://rlp.hds.harvard.edu/religions/buddhism/mahayana-great-vehicle&quot;&gt;Mahayana&lt;/a&gt; Buddhism developed in Tibet and associated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://rlp.hds.harvard.edu/religions/buddhism/vajrayana-diamond-vehicle&quot;&gt;Vajrayana&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.learnreligions.com/what-is-tantra-1770612&quot;&gt;Tantra&lt;/a&gt;. Its four major schools are Kagyü, Nyingma, Sakya, and Gelug; the “Ka-Nying” in “Ka-Nying Shedrub Ling” is short for “Kagyü and Nyingma”. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:57:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/about-gabriel-kendrea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/about-gabriel-kendrea</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Acclimating</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For me, the last couple of weeks have been focused around work and trying to understand the nuances of the project at hand.  Understandably, making improvements to the national health information system is an enormous task.  There are a dizzying number of pressing issues to address and that makes prioritization a challenge.  Next week I will travel to an outlying health facility to observe how clinical staff are trained to use the current version of the electronic health record software.  That will definitely be interesting to see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190821_151314.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An example of one of their health campaigns.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow there is a Trade Fair in a nearby town.  Hopefully that will provide lots of opportunities for photos.  Then on Monday we will have a day off from work for a national holiday.  We are planning to attend the festivities with some of our fellow Peace Corps volunteers.  As much as I am eager to dig into the work, I am happy to have the opportunity to relax a bit and see more of the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 13:58:14 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/acclimating</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/acclimating</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Busy roadsides</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I’d use this post to talk about something interesting I’ve noticed here. The country is relatively poor, with most people making less than $1 USD/day, but there is no end to the entrepreneurial spirit. Pretty much every roadside is dotted with various vendor stalls. Stands with roasted corn, fruit, salty snacks, and grilled meats to eat, buckets and water tanks, and the ever-present MTN data/airtime cards can be found all over the place. Other stands offer car washes, haircuts, or cell phone repair. Most of the stands are built out of poles (4-5″ diameter), pallets, or corrugated metal, or just the back of a truck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191207_121005-scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191207_120716-scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191207_120607-scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191207_121007-scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191207_121028-scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191127_151631-scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191127_145623-scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s super cool to see the many ways people find to make money. Crime is relatively low, despite the poverty, and instead lots of individual businesses abound. Even at work, it seems many people have a side hustle. Pay is low, even for professional jobs, so they are always on the lookout for opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/PANO_20191207_112341.vr_-scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A market within the Mbabane bus rank&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variety of items for sale includes clothing, shoes, soap, jewelry, hats, and much more. I’d love to publish more pictures, but it’s kind of hard to get images without asking lots of people for permission! I try to be sneaky and get shots when people are facing away, but that’s not always an option. If I can get more in the future, I’d love to post more!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 02:40:41 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/busy-roadsides</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/busy-roadsides</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Busy times in Eswatini!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to get to a post for a few weeks now, but it keeps getting pushed aside due to conflicting priorities. We’ve been hard at work trying to bring updates to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hmisswaziland.com/page/cmis.php&quot;&gt;CMIS&lt;/a&gt; (Client Management Information System), Eswatini’s EMR (Electronic Medical Records system). This involves adding new requested features, rearranging the code base to best support our needs, and working through bugs (existing ones and ones we’ve introduced!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we’ve spent hours inside and outside of work prototyping some new features for the system. Currently, CMIS is primarily used in almost 200 clinics for outpatient work, that is, visits that don’t involve checking into a hospital. Many of these clinics focus on HIV, TB, or other diseases, while also providing other regular medical services. Supporting the needs of an inpatient facility (a hospital) requires a very different way of working with the system, but is necessary to offer the best care at all points of service. There are still very many scenarios that require paper forms to capture data within a facility or to transfer information about a patient between facilities. No more paper!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All next week we will be participating in sessions with various stakeholders (doctors, nurses, regional representatives) as we try to come to consensus about some of these changes to make sure that we have buy-in for what’s likely to be some new ways of doing things in the system. Clinicians all have their own optimized workflows to deal with their patient load, and introducing an EMR (no matter how good) will also slow things down at first. We are hoping that with enough input, we can minimize this friction and make it a positive thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, the weather has continued to bounce up and down. On one day, sweating through my shirt on the way to work before 8am, then the next day wishing I had grabbed a jacket! There needs to be some work toward better weather management. I haven’t figured out who to complain to yet…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a gallery of pictures randomly representing our past two weeks or so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191101_160248.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191029_175108.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Roasted street corn&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191026_190219.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Indoor lizard eating a bug&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191104_072211.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wonderful breakfast from our landlords when power went out!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191101_161308.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191101_161735.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191103_094556.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mural I like. Click to zoom!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191102_132115.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A pickup truck full of chickens out and about&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191102_115455.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191102_131320.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Birds&amp;amp;#8217; nest on the ground&amp;amp;#8230;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191102_131315.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bird nests still in the tree&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/IMG_20191103_112421.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Baby veggies!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 11:33:39 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/busy-times-in-eswatini</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/busy-times-in-eswatini</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Categories</title>
        <description></description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:57:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/categories</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/categories</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Changing With the Seasons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The weather has turned, and with it, life is gently transitioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our host grandma has gotten sick with a cold. She constantly tells us to eat lots of hot food, wear sweaters, and wear slippers so that our feet don’t touch the cold marble. The temperature is… in the high 60s (Fahrenheit). Not so cold by Oregon standards!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4101.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grandma is wearing slippers under that long dress to keep her feet warm. Saili is on the right.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we reach the end of monsoon season, the mosquitos that carry dengue will disappear. We’ve asked maybe ten (!) pharmacies if they have any bug repellent left, and all but one have said no. It looks like our little lavender-scented spray bottle will persevere long enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Monday, it felt like the right time to get haircuts. My hair now dries much faster, stays out of my way, and (I think) looks pretty nifty! Gabriel briefly had a smooth face, but it yearns to remain hairy, so he already has a solid crop of stubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4103-2-e1568801211975-1024x769.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How this hair length came to be: We ducked into the first barber shop we saw. The dude who cut my hair looked about 16, he didn’t speak any English, and he clearly had very little experience. Despite these obstacles, both of my ears are intact. Gabriel’s barber pulled Gabriel’s face all over the place and spread many foamy substances on it. We were both treated to head and back massages afterward: they stretched our arms, popped our knuckles, and whacked us on the head with fists. We were surprised at all the physical contact, because Nepalis will usually never touch another person’s head, especially of someone of the opposite gender. As my mom said, maybe the 16-year-old enjoyed giving me a massage more than I enjoyed receiving it… Anyway, at the end, I saw a poster in Devanagari and figured out that it advertised haircuts for $1 (100 Nepali rupees), not $5 as they had told us. I kept quiet, figuring that this was still a good deal. I paid $10 (to cover both of us) and tried to leave, but then a barber asked for $7 more for the shave! Now that they were really trying to overcharge us, I pointed out the low price on the poster, and they let us go. I’m glad that we 1) gave them a tip because we could afford it, 2) didn’t let them totally rip us off, and best of all, 3) showed that foreigners might know more than they let on 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of September 18, we’ve been married as long in Nepal as in the United States!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we had a lovely time visiting Yuki’s apartment with Mesa and Jesus. We folded origami cranes for Mesa’s friend, who has cancer, as we chatted and I read an Anthropology textbook chapter out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4093-1-e1568801307734-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4096.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Look at all that corn by Yuki&amp;amp;#8217;s place. We&amp;amp;#8217;re basically in the Midwest!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I jotted down the nationalities of all of my Ethics classmates. (Since then, I’ve switched out of Ethics, but these proportions are pretty representative.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nepal (monk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;India&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Germany&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vietnam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bhutan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bhutan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ecuador&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netherlands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Germany&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brazil (nun)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;France/Switzerland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Russia (nun)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are going well. We’re glad we switched into different classes — the new ones are much more engaging and relevant to us. Gabriel and I both feel healthy now that we’ve settled into a routine with good exercise, rest, and food. This semester doesn’t need to be a huge adventure; we can treat it as a quiet retreat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4084.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Example of a good simple breakfast&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve updated the  to add members of our host family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a 2-minute &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/LzaC_GjciKU&quot;&gt;time-lapse &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/LzaC_GjciKU&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; of our 15-minute walk to school!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/59007344997__462cb59e-5c32-48ee-a8bf-cf764f226a06-e1568801363987-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nepali size 2XL is on the small side for Gabriel.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sending warm wishes for your own autumnal transitions!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 04:10:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/changing-with-the-seasons</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/changing-with-the-seasons</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>What We’re Here For: Classes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that we have four weeks of school behind us, we can share a more holistic view of what we’re studying!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our classmates are super diverse, not only in country of origin, but also educational background. Many have been devout Buddhists for years. Many new students have never written academic papers. Some have undergraduate degrees in Buddhist Studies and are here to get graduate degrees. Some are monks and nuns who memorize religious texts on a regular basis. Some older people have left careers in the West to deepen their religious practice. The vast majority speak English as a second language. I’m amazed that it works to cram us all in the same classroom and give us the same assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Khenpo Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have Khenpo class (a.k.a. Textual Studies 101, taught by a highly educated Tibetan monk) every day for 1.5 hours, plus a weekly 1-hour review class with the translator. (Side note: we enjoy hearing the translator speak Tibetan with Khenpo with her strong Russian accent.) We study one book — Shantideva’s &lt;em&gt;Bodhisattvacharyavatara&lt;/em&gt; — line by line. When we leave after four months of study, we will only be halfway through the book! Along the way, we draw on Tibetan Buddhist commentaries to learn theories, terms, lists, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Bodhisattvacharyavatara” translates to “The Way of the Bodhisattva”. A bodhisattva is a being who generates &lt;em&gt;bodhicitta&lt;/em&gt;, the wish to attain enlightenment for the sake of liberating all sentient beings from the painful cycle of rebirth. The goal in the Mahayana tradition, the largest branch of Buddhism, is to become an enlightened bodhisattva. Shantideva wrote this foundational text in the eighth century to guide ordinary beings on the bodhisattva path. Speaking of the bodhisattva path, here’s a chart I made that gives a good idea of the depth we’re going into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4162.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I worked hard to piece this together from offhand comments spread out over several days.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RYI’s Textual Studies courses are taught in the traditional format, in which monastics teach monastics. Therefore, even though Khenpo and the translator carefully accommodate the non-Buddhists in the class (nobody’s trying to convert us, we promise!), the structure of the course assumes a Buddhist audience. Consequently, we pray at the beginning and end of the class, and we’re required to memorize (I think) 30 verses of the text. Here’s a representative verse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Should bodhicitta come to birth Revered by all the world, by gods and humankind.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here’s the dedication prayer we say in Tibetan at the end of the class:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4161.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Khenpo leads the chanting in a low, rhythmic voice.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nepali Language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RYI takes its language classes seriously! We hear that Colloquial Tibetan, Classical Tibetan, and Sanskrit classes are much more difficult than Nepali, but we’re still working hard. We have an hour of “Master Class” with our lovely professor three times a week, an hour of one-on-one practice with native speakers twice a week, and an hour of “Boost Class” with four students and two native speakers once a week. That’s a total of six hours of language class every week. Since the class sizes are so small, we’re constantly put on the spot to speak individually. With all the classes, homework, daily life with a Nepali host family, and interactions with Nepali people around town, we’re learning pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4153.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A representative homework assignment. My handwriting is a bit messy because I wrote on my lap.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fun Facts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Kendrea” means “central” in Nepali and Hindi! Apparently it has positive connotations of mental concentration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can refer to others in either an honorific or informal way. A husband uses the informal pronoun for his wife. But… a wife must use the honorific pronoun for her husband. I can understand using informal both ways (because spouses know each other well) or honorific both ways (because spouses should respect each other), but the inequality is pretty gross.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dear Aunts Rennie, Ileana, Maria, and Ariadne: you are sisters of Gabriel’s father, so he can refer to each of you as “phoopoo” 😉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Anthropology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We regret to announce that Father Greg, our Buddhist Studies 205 professor, has been temporarily deported. The Nepali government bureaucracy makes it really difficult to maintain your visa! The class is supposed to take place for 1.5 hours twice a week, but we’ve only had three or four classes so far. We’ll write about it when we have more to say!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’m taking Fundamentals of Buddhist Philosophy (a.k.a. Buddhist Studies 203) without Gabriel. In this class, we study &lt;a href=&quot;https://tricycle.org/magazine/no-self-or-true-self/&quot;&gt;emptiness&lt;/a&gt;. We read and discuss one academic paper and one &lt;em&gt;sutra &lt;/em&gt;(story of the Buddha’s teachings) every week. This material is all pretty new to me and interesting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I switched out of the prerequisite class, so I’m having a bit of a hard time keeping track of all the terms that our professor, a Frenchwoman with an impressive American accent, tosses around. Besides, because this is a 200-level class, my experience with academic writing isn’t unusual! I’m not too concerned, though. I’ll just study a little harder and try to listen more than speak.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 02:41:51 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/classes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/classes</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Cooking in Japan – 日本で料理する</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190912_1842023489165067644657611.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The gas stove we bought about 2 months in&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cooking! A necessity and an enjoyable pastime, and not one of the things I thought would be any different from the States. I wasn’t completely wrong, but not completely right either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190808_074838880794140502247360.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Damian standing in our very bare kitchen&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we moved into our apartment, there were no appliances in it, at all. No stove, no fridge, no washing machine. Only a wall mounted air conditioner in the main room. There was a lowered section of counter meant for a counter top stove, you can kind of see it to Damian’s left in the picture above. There also was a space for the refrigerator, which was thankfully given to us a couple of days in along with a microwave. After a couple more weeks of instant food and cold lunches, we got a single electric induction burner! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190911_2148491076741911172622550.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our induction burner with a tamagoyaki pan and some grease on it&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been interesting, slowly collecting the things we need to cook like we’re at home. In Japan people generally don’t bake anywhere near as much as we do in the States, with the preferred methods of cooking being grilling and boiling. Nearly everything here is cooked on the stove, and large ovens that we have in America that heat with flame or electric coils are impossible to find. Even if we were to find one there would be nowhere to put it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/wp-1572091672413527861472594492855.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our little counter top three in one oven&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Japan what they have are basically souped up microwave-toasteroven-oven combos that use electricity to mimic the kind of direct heat you get with an oven or toaster oven. We gave in and bought one of these recently, and it’s really been a comfort to have. Aside from that, we do the majority of cooking on our two burner gas stove. It is very very hot, hotter than any gas range I’ve used before, and it’s been challenging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After going through all this trouble I think I can understand better why not many of the other ALTs here in Tome do much cooking, if any. If you already have terrible with cooking, coming to Japan will not make it any easier! Despite that, being able to have home cooked meals, especially some recipes from home, has been lovely. Nothing beats homesickness like the taste of home! Japanese food is delicious, but Japanese people do not spice their food nearly as liberally as we do! But I’ll leave that for another post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20191007_1855565774099552907883573.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Home made meat sauce&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 07:08:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/cooking-in-japan-%25e6%2597%25a5%25e6%259c%25ac%25e3%2581%25a7%25e6%2596%2599%25e7%2590%2586%25e3%2581%2599%25e3%2582%258b</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/cooking-in-japan-%25e6%2597%25a5%25e6%259c%25ac%25e3%2581%25a7%25e6%2596%2599%25e7%2590%2586%25e3%2581%2599%25e3%2582%258b</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Coronavirus</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this brief post to give everyone an update on the situation here in Japan. Some of you may have heard that Abe Shinzo, Japan’s prime minister, made an announcement last week that all of the schools in Japan would be closed for the next several weeks. It was really a suggestion, but as my school district decided to close school, you may be wondering what all this means for Damian and I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, our day-to-day doesn’t really change. Damian isn’t affected at all, as he works from home, and I’m actually still going to work. School is closed for the kids, but teachers are actually still required to go in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for the next month until the new school year, I’m going to be spending a lot of time at my desk. I will probably be doing prep, Japanese language study, and discreet reading. In all honesty, I’m probably going to be extremely bored for the next month until the new school year starts (The school year starts in April in Japan). However, I will still be working and it’s pretty much business as usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damian and I are doing fine, and we’re mildly amused with the antics of some people overreacting to the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look forward to some older posts that we’ve been working on! We’ll be sure to keep everyone updated with the goings on out here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 01:30:17 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/coronavirus</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/coronavirus</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Corvallis to Singapore</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re in Asia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adventure began on Thursday. I was feeling much better after finishing a two-week course of antibiotics that left me tired and nauseous. We finished up our two-week house-sitting gig by taking the elderly labradoodle, Tanner, on a lovely walk around the neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets&quot; alt=&quot;We&amp;amp;#8217;ll miss the quiet natural beauty of Oregon.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished packing at my parents’ house, and then my family escorted us to Portland by way of a healthy dinner out. We met up with Dr. Barstow, Mesa, and Kalie to trade stories over a leisurely second dinner (paid for by Dr. Barstow’s ridiculous frequent-flyer rewards). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We four hopped to San Francisco, then got on a gigantic Singapore Airlines plane for the 15-hour nighttime flight to Hong Kong. It certainly helped that the flight attendants handed out hot towels and two warm meals, but a flight that long is bound to be uncomfortable! (We’ve eaten at least twice the usual number of meals for this timeframe…) We arrived at the Hong Kong airport without a single hitch. In fact, it was eerie that we saw zero signs of the recent protests. We had a layover long enough to go “Whoaaaa we’re in China”, and then we congregated again to return to the exact same seats. It’s a good thing, too! Turns out we’ve had a super cool seatmate this entire time. Ananya is a junior (like me!) studying Computer Science, Data Science, and Product Design at UC Berkeley, and she’s headed home to Singapore. Just like the protagonist of the book I listened to while sitting next to her on the 14-hour flight, she comes from a Sikh Punjabi family. We’ve had quite a lot to talk about on this flight from Hong Kong to Singapore — school, work, mental health, politics, religion, travel, programming languages, how I fainted into Gabriel’s arms while I received a shot in the butt two days after our wedding, and so on. Look Mom, we’re socializing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets&quot; alt=&quot;We flew directly over Lilly and Damian on the way from San Francisco to Hong Kong!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 19:34:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/corvallis-to-singapore</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/corvallis-to-singapore</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Counting down the hours…</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Less than 24 hours to go for Arian and Karen until getting on the first plane! Preparing has been more difficult than expected. We’ve moved before, but this time we need to decide for every item if we are giving away, selling, storing, or bringing with us. How much do we bring for a year? How much of our stuff do we really need to store? Selling off our house and cars is somewhat liberating, but trying to be sure we are bringing everything we need is a challenge. We can’t just Amazon Prime a forgotten item! On the other hand, there will be stores (it is the capitol city!), and maybe there will be some kind of internet delivery possible. We’ll just have to see. It’s going to be a grand adventure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/08/wp-1564613485190.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 17:39:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/counting-down-the-hours</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/counting-down-the-hours</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>December in Eswatini</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It seemed strange to be preparing for Christmas with the sun shining so warmly.  To help get into the holiday spirit, Arian joined a small singing group.  They lead Christmas caroling at a community center in town.  The kids joined right in and a good time was had by all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191217_173351.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191217_183050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had the opportunity to attend a youth Christmas concert.  The event was organized by a Taiwanese program that provides musical instruction to high-risk youth.  They teach the children traditional Swazi dance, western choral music, and orchestral instruments.   At the same time, they provide apprenticeships for local musicans who are interested in learning to be instructors.  It was a lot of fun to see how much the program has accomplished in only two years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191208_162837.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191208_151226.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191208_154234.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most exciting thing about December was knowing that we would soon be seeing Damian, Lilly, Gabriel, and Kendrea in Japan! We will be with them for two weeks. Definitely makes the year easier!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191219_083022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191219_210352.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191220_155824.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191220_174810.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_20191220_194126-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 05:33:16 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/december-in-eswatini</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/december-in-eswatini</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Dog dog dog dog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Kathmandu has many street dogs. I don’t know much, but I do know that they often lead tough lives and their bites are responsible for the vast majority of human rabies cases in Nepal. Some look chubby and healthy; others look skinny, injured, and afflicted by various ailments. They’re territorial, so they often get into loud fights about who gets to live where. , Chökyi Nyima Rinpoche’s charity, works hard for their welfare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the cute dog photos…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4183.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yawning with cafe dog&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4188.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;There was another one, too&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4181.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;And they hung out with Gabriel&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4165-e1571860094826-769x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4231.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mouthy Girl! She lives right outside our house, and she endearingly hangs her mouth open all the time. Lately, she’s been licking more than nipping.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 03:34:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/dog-dog-dog-dog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/dog-dog-dog-dog</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Family Christmas in Japan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks of December ended up being our first leave from Peace Corps. From the start, we wanted to visit Gabriel and Kendrea in Nepal, and Damian and Lilly in Japan. Unfortunately, it’s hard to get much leave in the first few months, plus the cost was horrendous, so we didn’t end up going to Nepal. Instead, we went to Japan with a bonus: Gabriel and Kendrea finished their study abroad and were going through Japan on their way home to Oregon! We were there for two weeks and stayed at Damian and Lilly’s apartment in Sanuma (in Tome).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took a shuttle bus to Johannesburg so we could fly out of O.R. Tambo International Airport, then had a layover in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. We even made a quick stop in Seoul, Korea for reasons I still don’t understand, but necessitated everyone leaving, going through security screening again, then re-boarding. Definitely wasn’t some emergency thing since we did it both ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191220_193327.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We made it!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We landed in Narita and took a train to a guesthouse for the night. It was a great little place very close to a historic street. In the morning, we walked down the street, and got fire-roasted yams and chestnuts from different street vendors. We talked to Karen’s brother Dan and he highly recommended that we go to a close by temple complex, so we headed over there. It was quite beautiful and I’m glad we could go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191221_121614.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191221_122558.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191221_122811.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting back to the guesthouse, we met a guy named Ignacio who was from Belgium and was finishing up a year-long bike ride around the world! We chatted for a bit and got insanely jealous. He’s been to so many places and gotten to see so much. Places I wouldn’t normally think of as safe enough to visit, let alone to cycle through! You can read more about him on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nacho-on-a-bike.com/&quot;&gt;his blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damian and Lilly met up with us in Tokyo and we spent two nights there. Tokyo is a great city! So many things to see. We took the train wherever we went (public transit can be so liberating!) and went to several areas. We also spent a number of hours at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edo-tokyo-museum.or.jp/en/about/&quot;&gt;Edo Museum&lt;/a&gt;. So many great exhibits showcasing the Edo period. I love miniature models/dioramas, and this place had so many!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191222_151059.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191222_151411-rotated.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191222_155608.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191222_160527.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also went to the St. Nicholas cathedral (ok, so it’s actually called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.japantravel.com/tokyo/nikolai-do-orthodox-cathedral/5435&quot;&gt;Holy Resurrection Cathedral&lt;/a&gt;) and were able to attend liturgy. It was so wonderful since there’s no Orthodox church in Eswatini. I couldn’t understand it, but I was able to follow along in an English-language book and sing along phonetically. Saint Nicholas and the cathedral are actually pretty big deals in Tokyo. Since there are so few Christians, the bells are a bit unusual and well-known. The Edo Museum even had a recording of the bells to accompany their model!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191222_094300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Locally referred to as Nikolaido-do (Home of Nicholas)&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went up to Damian and Lilly’s place and got settled in. The next day, we drove to Sendai Station (not as far as Tokyo) to pickup Gabriel and Kendrea. Now our group was the full six. It was such a wonderful feeling being around all of them after so long! That’s definitely the hardest part of being so far away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the visit, we played games, talked, and saw various sites in the region. We were consistently amazed with the number of vending machines out and about! Pretty much every block, you’d see one, two, six different machines. Mostly beverages, but it was very cool to see machines where the cans of hot drinks were actually hot! Coffee, cocoa, corn soup, all ready to go. It’s hard to imagine how they get enough business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191229_160913.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hot? Cold? They got you covered!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you couldn’t get enough from the machines, there were convenience stores (&lt;em&gt;kombini&lt;/em&gt;s) every few blocks. One chain called Lawson, and then quite a few 7-11’s. Food was readily available and reasonably priced. The only real issues were reading the labels, and my stupid celiac gut. It turns out that the Japanese &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; love their soy sauce. No, I mean &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt;. It was hard to find almost anything prepared that was safe. Thankfully, Lilly was able to check the ingredient lists, and I was also able to use my phone to translate. It was definitely disappointing to be restricted like that. We were fine buying our own supplies and cooking back at the apartment though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our stay we saw a number of different temples. They’re quite beautiful. We also saw a windmill! It was a gift from the Dutch and installed at Naganuma Futopia Park. They also had a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; long slide with rollers for the surface. It was probably for kids, but it didn’t stop all of us from having great fun on it too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191229_150214-rotated.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191229_145129.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191229_145339.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we left, we saw the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toyoma_Education_Museum&quot;&gt;Toyoma Education Museum&lt;/a&gt; in Tome which portrays a typical Japanese elementary school in the late 1800’s with lots of interesting exhibits in former classrooms. The next morning, on our way to the station, we visited the town of Ishinomaki. This was a town very heavily hit during the tsunami a few years ago, losing many children and other people in the flooding. It was sad to see how much recovery there still was left, though it was clear there was also incredible progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our last stop was in the touristy town of Matsushima. It was a beautiful place with ocean views and a gorgeous park. Due to the features of their bay, they were somewhat protected during the tsunami and sustained less damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191231_135854.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191231_135928.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191231_140005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191231_140059.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some difficulty, we said our good-byes at the station. It’s never easy. Kendrea was to have an internship interview the next morning, and she and Gabriel would be getting ready for their own departure back to the US. We took the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.japan-guide.com/e/e2018.html&quot;&gt;Shinkansen&lt;/a&gt; (bullet train) to Tokyo. It went as fast as 140mph! Definitely a great way to travel, though the price was outrageous…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191231_152011.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Leaving the station (don&amp;amp;#8217;t worry, not ours!)&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now back home in Eswatini, safe and sound (and Gabriel/Kendrea also home, for real), it’s time to settle back in and get back to work. I’m so glad we were able to make the trip, but it was a difficult departure. We already can’t wait to see them all again!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 03:31:46 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/family-christmas-in-japan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/family-christmas-in-japan</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>First week of work!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190828_1621495750316979766221289.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello again from Japan! Last week was my first week of work as an ALT at three elementary schools in Tome City. I visited my main school three times, and my secondary schools once each. This will be the normal schedule for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first week was full mainly of introduction classes. I have the class period to introduce my students to me, to Oregon, and to my family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started most classes by talking and taking questions about Oregon. Kids were usually surprised that we have desert in Oregon, and they were excited to talk about it. Japan doesn’t have any areas that can be called a desert, so this is something they’ve never really seen before. They were also generally surprised that there are wolves living in Oregon, because they were eradicated in Japan a while ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I talked about my family and told everyone I was married they were impressed I think! If I told them to guess my age before telling them I was married they were pretty close to the mark, but if it was after I got ten years added to my age! I think this is because it is extremely uncommon for Japanese people to get married before 27 or 28. They were also always excited to hear about my family pets, Sara and Griffin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day at school both the students and teachers eat &lt;em&gt;kyushoku&lt;/em&gt;, or school lunch. Everyone eats the same food, and it’s usually very good food. Children serve each other their lunch in the classroom, with those serving changing regularly. I eat either in the teacher’s room or with one of the students’ classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/wp-15673974273187584358798771353574.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjusting to teaching has been a little difficult so far. Some of the teachers I work with don’t know any English beyond what they teach, which can make commutation difficult. They’re also very busy, making lesson planning very touch and go. So far things have been going well though! I’m looking forward to seeing the kids I work with grow as people and as English speakers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 23:13:55 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/first-week-of-work</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/first-week-of-work</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Getting down to business</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week is all about setting up our new apartment and going to work. We arrived at our new place on Monday after our swearing-in. We went over in a truck along with our belongings, accompanied by a truck with items supplied by the Peace Corps which included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blanket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sheets and pillowcases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pots and pans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flatware, cutlery, cups/bowls/plates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large basin and buckets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gas cooking stove&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us, everything was doubled since we each get a set, but instead of two stoves, they increased the two-burner to a three. The list is tailored to volunteers in rural areas so not everything applies as much to us. The large basin is for bathing (!) and the buckets for hauling water. We really lucked out with our place since we have a full kitchen that included cups/bowls/plates, and a regular bathroom with shower (no need for baths in a basin!). The gas cooking stove is to use if electricity goes out, which it does from time to time, even in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190813_10433343963134887585369.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking from the street to the bed and breakfast. We are on the right side around back.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our place is simple, but very nice. The living room and bedroom are one room, with a separate kitchen and bathroom. We have a small patio with a table and two chairs outside. The place is run as a B&amp;amp;B, so there is a laundry machine available and several small units for our family and friends to use when they visit (hint, hint!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets&quot; alt=&quot;Our own little corner&amp;amp;#8230;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After moving in on Monday, we ran around to a number of stores on Tuesday to get supplies that we needed. There are quite a number of food, clothing, and general merchandise stores around us so we found most of what we needed. We feel like it’s going to work out nicely here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, we went in for our first day of work. We will be working in the offices of the Ministry of Health with the team working on their electronic medical records system. This involves gathering the requirements, creating a usable system, collecting the right data, and reporting on the indicators needed by eSwatini and the various international agencies. Their biggest priority is reducing HIV infection rates and improving treatment, but a good medical records system makes it easier to focus on a healthy population across a variety of indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one day, we met quite a few people, and will hopefully remember at least of few of their names! There are many subgroups in the department with many responsibilities. They are well-focused on what needs to be done, but right now it’s a long list. We are excited to get up to speed on their systems and processes so we can hopefully contribute soon!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 14:02:48 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/getting-down-to-business</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/getting-down-to-business</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Getting started!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We landed at King Mswati III International airport. It was very nice, but amazingly quiet compared to the last few airports! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190803_1343443512505063701213003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The airport had large photos of the king, the queen mother, and the prime minister. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190803_1347417583044889310976326.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customs was quick and painless and we were on our way thanks to a ride in a comfortable van courtesy of the program director. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190803_1348461420359981843385864.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the airport, we had over an hour’s drive to Manzini where we are staying. The entire drive we saw roads under construction and relatively low traffic. Along the road there were unfenced cows and goats, along with many vendor stalls with fruits, baskets, bowls, and roasted corn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190803_143928__017881765053911507715.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re finally here and ready to get started. “Here” is the campus of the Institute of Development Management, where Peace Corps has dorms and classrooms. Everyone is doubling up to reduce room count. Fortunately they let Karen and me be roomies! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190803_1613272906782458776960498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found out that we won’t get local sim cards until Monday. That means no data, SMS, etc. It would have been nice to know we’d have data blackout for the first two days!Our cohort consists of eight people, including us. Three of them are medical along with one in sociology, there to teach, one is a videographer shooting training and other videos, then there’s a programmer I’ll be working with, plus Karen and me. One did regular Peace Corps years ago, the rest of us are green. No one is much more prepared for what to expect than we are.Today and tomorrow we have some brief orientation sessions. The pre-training lasts a week and starts Monday. During that time we’ll be doing language and culture lessons, lots of PC rules and policies, and learning more about our positions. It looks to be a pretty busy time. We’ll be trying out “normal” sleep schedules. We’ll see how it goes!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 05:54:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/getting-started</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/getting-started</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Ginger</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some people may know that Japan, and Asian countries in general, like their ginger. It’s used frequently in many different dishes and is popular in candy and drinks. Ginger also plays a particularly large role in sushi, where the reddish picked slices are eaten with pretty much any form of rice and fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/sushi_ginger_250.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Random internet picture with a big pile of ginger.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since ginger is so popular, and since I rather enjoy eating ginger, we thought it might be fun to try to make some of our own pickled ginger. The process isn’t that hard and makes some pretty yummy ginger!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191116_182209823.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Ginger root, not quite edible yet&amp;amp;#8230;. *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is peeling the ginger root. The skin is tough and fibery. Also, we don’t have a potato peeler or anything, so I had to use our knife to cut the skin off. Overall, this was the most time consuming and difficult step (it’s really not a hard process).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191116_190820550.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*All peeled! *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to cut the ginger into thin slices. There’s nothing precise about this step, we just want small pieces to make it easier to eat with stuff later. Our mandolin doesn’t have any settings for thickness, so our slices are thicker than you’d usually find at a restaurant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191116_191937756_MP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Lilly helped with this picture&amp;amp;#8230;.* Ginger all sliced&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we need to put the slices in a jar and prepare our pickling juice. Now I should mention that we’re not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; pickling the ginger in the normal way. We’re going to do what’s called a quick pickle. The brine/juice is a mix of vinegar, water, sugar, salt, and spices such as anise if that’s your jam. We boiled the mixture with ginger sprouts, but they didn’t really give much flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191116_193050702.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*All packed in and ready to go! *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the mixture has been brought to a boil and left to simmer for a few min, the juice/brine is poured over the ginger and allowed to cook for a few min before sealing it and putting it in the fridge. Since this isn’t a real pickle, we don’t have to worry about gas build up in the jar – the container can be sealed and the pickle will brine for a few days at minimum. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191116_193522457.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*You can already see the ginger is turning the liquid a slight pinkish color*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those that don’t know, raw ginger is quite strong and fibery. The vinegar and sugar will help sweeten and subdue the strong ginger flavor as well as break down the fibers a bit. That said, it’s still very gingery and has lots of fibers, just not as bad as raw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191126_075615823.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Final product, more pink! *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20191126_075743571.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*The ginger developed a slight pink color, younger ginger would get more color. *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the ginger didn’t turn quite as red as I was expecting, but apparently that’s due to the age of the ginger, younger = more pink. Though 2 days is the minimum for good ginger this way, ours sat for 2 weeks and is much better for it! The flavor is very good, still stronger than most restaurant grade stuff, but I prefer strong ginger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Random ginger facts from the internet, pickled ginger has slight anti-microbial properties which may help in the consumption of raw food (fish mostly). Also, the vibrant pink often seen in restaurant ginger is because they add food coloring!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 17:19:27 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/ginger</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/ginger</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Goodbye Nepal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings from 1:00 in the morning, somewhere over southeast Asia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to catch you up on our final three weeks in Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went on lots of little errands to prepare to leave. We enjoyed finding new parts of town. Gabriel really likes the traditional architecture, so here’s a representative door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_4876.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t usually drink coffee, but we enjoyed studying at the Western-style coffee shop and expanding our coffee horizons. We sometimes even got the coveted stupa-view seats by the windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_4887.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Himalayan Java Coffee is a chain that was founded in Nepal. They&amp;amp;#8217;ve even expanded to the US now.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that Nepal has a holiday for eating grapefruit, so instead of our usual one-on-one language partner class, all the Nepali language partners cooked up a grapefruit dish for all of the students! It was a truly bizarre concoction, with grapefruit, milk (we had a special milk-free version), peanuts, chillies, mustard oil, sugar, sesame seeds, spices, and who knows what all else. We sat around in a circle on the stage at the monastery cafe to eat it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_4851.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;We were told that the grapefruit peels should go on our heads, but I am highly suspicious about this&amp;amp;#8211;only the foreigners wore grapefruit hats!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_4855.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our host family had some shelves installed, so of course they called up the shelf bike dude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/65ffd467-76e7-4006-8fed-c68e74b2338f.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;What, how else would you transport your furniture?&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sang in the Boudha Community Chorale Christmas concert! It turned out to be quite the fancy affair. It took place at the monastery cafe, so we enjoyed a feast of fusion food afterward. It didn’t start out very auspiciously from our perspective–we took an accidental midday nap that made us late and then two people had to help get Gabriel’s tie on–but the singing part went well! The Boudha Community Chorale (mostly foreigners) hosted the concert; the British Model College Choir (all Nepali students) and the Kathmandu String Ensemble (all Nepali adults) also performed. The musical quality wasn’t up to the standards we’re used to in Corvallis, but it was still a pretty special experience to sing the Hallelujah Chorus at the top of our lungs with a large, diverse musical ensemble at a beautifully lit Buddhist outdoor cafe in Kathmandu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/DSC08795.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Boudha Community Chorale&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/DSC08844.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;All set up at Utpala Cafe&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swing club wrapped up very well! Seven people, including us, participated in the final lesson. We taught our most advanced students tandem Charleston while Yuki gave beginner lessons to some newer folks. We danced, sang, and laughed to a playlist of holiday swing music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_4912.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;We don&amp;amp;#8217;t have any more photos of swing club, so here&amp;amp;#8217;s Mouthy Girl.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished finals!! We worked really hard, and we think it paid off (no real-time grading like we’re used to back home, so we’ll need to wait for final grades to come in). I began this semester assuming that I could use my pre-existing philosophy essay skills, but I finally accepted that this school requires a different frame of mind. For my final paper, instead of bringing in my own science-y perspective like I would for philosophy papers at OSU, I tried sticking very closely to traditional Tibetan sources (translated to English, of course). I enjoyed stretching myself in this way, and I think it’s more in line with what the instructors intended. Don’t think that we had too much fun, though. They were still finals. Much stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_4917-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Look at those sources. Am I a real scholar now?&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather has been warm and sunny. Here’s Yuki demonstrating that one can comfortably snuggle with dogs outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_4930-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our last few days in Nepal were pretty pleasant, too. The Himalayas came out to greet us on a clear day. We delivered thank-you notes, recycled lots of class papers, did last-minute shopping around the stupa, had a serendipitous dinner with our friend Tia, and even visited Chökyi Nyima Rinpoche. We listened as he had conversations with other visitors in Tibetan and Nepali. We only spoke with him briefly, but it was lovely to bask in his kind glow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_4943.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in Japan!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 04:53:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/goodbye-nepal</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/goodbye-nepal</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Hello world!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the journal of Kulp travels!  Stay up-to-date on where we are around the world and the good and bad things happening.  We’ll try to make new posts frequently to keep people informed and as a log of our own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 10:48:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/hello-world</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/hello-world</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Home at Last</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Corvallis a month and a half ago, and wow, it feels like a lot of time has passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Looking Back on Nepal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if living in Nepal taught us the meaning of life. It’s not quite so straightforward, though. Here are the real results of our time abroad:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By living in a very different place, we simply learned more about how the world can function. It turns out that near-anarchy (no traffic laws, no sanitation laws, no zoning, etc.) can kinda work. We think that the West should have more Nepali-style buildings with flat roofs for hanging out on, clotheslines, solar water heating, no central heating or AC, etc. These buildings have a smaller environmental impact with minimal impact on comfort (in the right climate, anyway).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have new confidence that we can figure out food/water safety, public transit, taxis, restaurants, etc. just about anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ve had lots of time to learn about, talk about, and reflect on religions (mostly Buddhism). We’re happy to talk your ear off about it anytime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have an alarming amount of Kathmandu dust and pollution in our lungs. In general, our immune systems have been through a lot, possibly for the better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeing suffering people and animals every day strongly reminded us to help others as much as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have very mixed feelings about future travel. On one hand, we love Oregon and we’ve had enough of the hassles of traveling (not to mention the expense and environmental impact). On the other hand, we find ourselves absentmindedly looking up job openings in Estonia and Singapore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While still in Nepal, as we were planning our travels to Japan, we expected that we would lightheartedly joke about the cultural transition. Nope, we had a genuinely difficult time adjusting to all the differences! We both caught ourselves nodding sideways (the Nepali way) on several occasions. We felt indignant that we had just gone through all this effort to learn a new language (Nepali), yet we still couldn’t understand the (Japanese) speech of the people around us. It was hard, but it also provided a convenient transition period to minimize culture shock in the States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We stayed in Nepal for just the right amount of time. We thoroughly enjoyed having enough time to truly settle into Boudha, but Nepal doesn’t feel like home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, we studied religion for just the right amount of time. It was really wonderful to be immersed in the monastery school and debate with nuns over lunch. At the same time, it feels good to study technology, math, and science again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To generalize, we reaffirmed the importance of balance. In the past, we wished for more chances to explore the world and more time to think about topics like religion, philosophy, and anthropology; I missed learning languages. In Nepal, though, we missed family+friends, the coziness of crafting, our musical instruments, and tech+math+science. It’ll be an ongoing challenge to give all of these priorities the attention they deserve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Our New Living Arrangement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We really lucked out! Our university’s family housing has a waitlist over a year long and we made it to the top right on time. Additionally, there are a variety of sizes and costs to the units, and you have to take the one that’s available when you finish your wait. We got the perfect size and budget, and our particular unit was remodeled right before we moved in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now we have a nice one-bedroom apartment that’s about a 7-minute walk from the edge of campus, on a quiet street, with good internet, and all utilities included. We’re having a good time making the space our own (by cooking a lot of Nepali food, for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Kendrea’s had to spend a lot of time out of the apartment. More on that after the pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/02/img_5096.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/02/img_5092-1-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/02/img_5091-1-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/02/img_5212.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What We’re Up To&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Gabriel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have quite the set of classes compared to what we took in Nepal! I’m taking a full course load of computer science, physics, and (surprisingly) geography. Here’s a brief description of each:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analysis of Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;: Basically the class so far has been, “here’s an impossible-sounding task. Solve it.” followed by confusion, then ideas, then a solution. Some people complain that this kind of work won’t be useful in industry, but I only really want a job where it would be…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming Language Fundamentals&lt;/strong&gt;: Programming is telling a computer what to do. There are many different philosophies to accomplish this, and this class talks about the unique challenges in defining and evaluating the grammar and semantics of a language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy Alternatives&lt;/strong&gt;: A 7-person physics colloquium about the physical limits of classical and alternative energy sources. We talk about the benefits and drawbacks of coal, natural gas, hydro, wave, geothermal, wind, solar, nuclear, biomass, and many other sources of energy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Weird World of Quantum Mechanics&lt;/strong&gt;: Another very small physics colloquium about the nature of reality at the smallest testable and verifiable scale. In contrast to most other physics classes, the only inclusion of math is to demonstrate relationships. The class is mostly theory and discussion. The same professor teaches colloquia other terms about the physics and philosophy of time and consciousness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geography of International Development and Globalization&lt;/strong&gt;: Why are some countries rich and others poor? How have people tried to explain this in the past, and what did they get wrong? This class is about how the expansion of capitalism and colonialism left marks on the globalized world we’re in today. There’s also a lot of discussion of the effects of a growing population and shifting labor market. Each student picks a country to focus on throughout the term, so I picked Eswatini!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been surviving the transition from monastery coursework alright, and I got used to having an apartment right by campus pretty quickly. My proximity has also facilitates extracurriculars like participation in security club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m studying computer science with a focus on computer security. This term, through the security club, I’ve joined a group of six other students to compete in the Pacific Rim Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition, in which you take on the task of running a mock company’s server infrastructure in the face of professional hackers… who are way better at attacking than anyone is at defending. And they’re also scouts from big companies looking to hire. And you have to defend the network for two 8-hour blocks over a weekend. We did well in the qualifiers last week, and everyone is optimistic about our performance in Seattle coming up at the end of March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Kendrea&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m working at &lt;a href=&quot;http://galois.com&quot;&gt;Galois&lt;/a&gt;! Surprise! Gabriel and I have been excited about Galois for a long time now. I received an internship offer while in Japan; as of February 2, I’ve now finished two weeks of a ten-week internship. It’s a shame that I have to spend 3-5 days a week in Portland so soon after arriving in the States, but it’s worth it to hang out with a concentrated group of ridiculously kind and smart people. My goal is to sneakily convince them that Gabriel, as a fellow ridiculously kind and smart person, belongs there, too. I’ve spent most of my work time so far studying up on functional programming (Scala), abstract algebra (category theory), and epistemology (Quine). I’m working with a philosopher at a tech company named after a mathematician—I love that I usually can’t even tell if I’m doing philosophy, computer science, or math! Just today, I jumped in on a new project to consolidate models in an effort to identify interventions that would alleviate food insecurity in Ethiopia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank you!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…for following along, listening to our stories, and supporting us!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 23:46:30 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/home-at-last</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/home-at-last</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Homestay: Here to Stay</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, we OSU students packed up our things, checked out of Shechen Guest House, trekked in the heat to RYI (we really don’t recommend walking with rolling suitcases in Kathmandu), met our host families, and headed home with them for the first time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gabriel and I are staying in a three-story house in a fancy part of town with two brothers (Roshan and Milan) who work in the financial sector, their mother (Ranju), Milan’s 10-year-old son (Ishan), and at least one servant (Saili). Roshan is married, but his wife and son live in another house with his in-laws (and now Mesa from OSU!). The third floor consists of Roshan’s bedroom, our bedroom, a shared living room, a shared bathroom and a nifty two-level balcony. Roshan and Milan speak English pretty well, Grandma and Ishan speak a little, and Saili speaks none, but I’ve bonded a lot with her just by smiling and gesturing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3933.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our room&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3934.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Proof that our desk was once clean&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3982.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Third-floor living room&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3983.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A fancy version of the typical Nepali bathroom: bidet, spigot, and no shower curtain. We bought the toilet paper ourselves.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3984.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View from the roof, right above our room&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The family members belong to the highest Hindu caste — Brahmin — so Gabriel and I, as outcastes, have to avoid ritually polluting them or their home with our presence. We stay out of the kitchen and shrine area. Menstruating women aren’t allowed in the kitchen. (Nepal is mostly Hindu, so it’s not a surprise that we’re staying with a Hindu family. We’re studying Buddhism, though, which does not have a caste system.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3985.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The shrine is at the very top of the stairs.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Milan and Roshan have crazy busy work schedules, so we’ve spent by far the most time with Grandma. Saili and Grandma serve us food and clear our dishes. It’s a constant struggle to insist that we’re full and don’t need any more food! Grandma sits with us as we eat. She used to teach Nepali language, so she has taken it upon herself to teach us a bunch! Between Nepali lessons during RYI orientation and informal lessons with Grandma, I estimate we’ve learned 100 words so far. Not bad for three days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food is DELICIOUS. They cook nearly the same thing for lunch and dinner every single day: dal (lentil soup), bhat (rice), tarkari (vegetable curry), Nepali salad (just cucumber and carrot), and achar (various kinds of spicy pickles, analogous to salsa). It’s my favorite cuisine, so I don’t mind the repetition at all. Plus, you can imagine that you get &lt;em&gt;really &lt;/em&gt;good at cooking something when you make it twice a day for decades! I really hope that Grandma or Saili will agree to give us cooking lessons sometime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3977.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Meals are no-phone zones, so I snuck this picture when Grandma left the room mid-meal. I mixed together my dal, bhat, and tarkari on the bottom. At the top from left to right, you can see crunchy seasoned soybeans, pea salad with ginger and vinegar, and &amp;amp;#8220;baby French fries&amp;amp;#8221; (as Gabriel calls them).&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3981.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dining room table&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3979.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Maybe it’s a good thing Gabriel isn’t expected to cook&amp;amp;#8230; the kitchen is a bit small for him!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: our intrepid guide Dr. Barstow went home to Oregon a week ago. It was great having him along, but we don’t mind the increased independence now that we have our feet under us!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 04:44:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/homestay-here-to-stay</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/homestay-here-to-stay</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re going to Nepal! And we’re blogging about it. We hope that the blog will help us keep in touch with friends and family, share what we learn, and remember the trip in future years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We leave mid-August and return late December 2019. We’ll live near Kathmandu (Nepal’s capital). Specifically, we’ll stay with a host family in the town of Boudhanath, which has a rich Tibetan-influenced culture. (The Himalayan mountain range divides Nepal from the China-controlled Tibetan plateau.) We’ll attend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ryi.org/&quot;&gt;Rangjung Yeshe Institute&lt;/a&gt;, an international school based at a Tibetan Buddhist monastery called &lt;a href=&quot;https://shedrub.org/&quot;&gt;Ka-Nying Shedrub Ling&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll both take classes in Buddhist Philosophy and Hermeneutics, Anthropology of Nepalese Religion, and Nepali Language. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We owe this opportunity to &lt;a href=&quot;https://thelostyak.com/an-introduction/&quot;&gt;Dr. Geoff Barstow&lt;/a&gt; from the School of History, Philosophy, and Religion at Oregon State University (OSU). Last fall, he visited my World Religions class to talk about this study abroad opportunity. I immediately got super excited, but didn’t have much hope that I could actually go. As a concession, I signed up for his course about Buddhist ethics in the spring. Then, we learned about the plans Lilly &amp;amp; Damian and Karen &amp;amp; Arian had for the year… suddenly, moving halfway across the world ourselves seemed less ridiculous! Dr. Barstow turned out to be an outstanding and highly approachable professor, so we had plenty of chances to ask him questions about studying abroad. We’ve met the other five students from OSU who will also go on this trip: Jesus (who was in my Buddhist ethics class), Kalie (whose best friend we know from Gabriel’s church), Yuki (who I helped with German pronunciation in choir last year), Yi-Hsiang (whose family lives near Tibet), and Mesa (who goes to OSU-Cascades in Bend, Oregon). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like a refresher at any time about who we are and what we’re talking about, see our biography and glossary on the “&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.kulpfamily.org/about-gabriel-kendrea/&quot;&gt;About Gabriel &amp;amp; Kendrea&lt;/a&gt;” page. Please keep in touch! For our part, we’ll do our best to keep this interesting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets&quot; alt=&quot;At this point, we have no idea what any of this means except &amp;amp;#8220;Institute&amp;amp;#8221;.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 11:31:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/introduction</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/introduction</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>January in Eswatini</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One more week left of January. Nothing exciting since our return. We did get to go on a hike with some other volunteers to the top of Sibebe Rock, also called Execution Rock. It looks like a hill, but is actually the largest rock in the world (depending on who you ask…). It was some beautiful landscape with some trails through fields, grazing cattle, and even a lone horse!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/PANO_20200104_062518.vr_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I felt a little like we were a fellowship of sorts&amp;amp;#8230;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left way too early in the morning after waking up around 5am. I am not a morning person, so this was not an easy feat! We took a taxi to a starting point and just started walking the nearest path, hoping that it was the right away! We ended up walking through a homestead where we were given friendly help and they removed a section of their fence so we could walk through!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20200104_063822.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Such a beautiful valley&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the walk was along a rough road that was crazy narrow and steep in parts. I can’t imagine having to drive it! At one point, we saw some grass bundled together to be used on a thatch roof. It was pretty cool just seeing them lying there drying out. We also walked past a cave/alcove where a horse was hanging out. Unfortunately, I didn’t have my camera ready in time to get a shot of him still in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20200104_081548.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20200104_065157.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20200104_094154.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hike ended up being several hours and was pretty tiring overall. Having started earlier, it wasn’t too hot until toward the end. I don’t think we could have done it much later!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/PANO_20200104_070208.vr_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rolling hills all over&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also walked past people working in their fields of corn and other crops. The area is on the outer edges of Mbabane so much more rural than we see day-to-day. It was so nice getting away for a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/PANO_20200104_082426.vr_.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sitting on a lower part of Sibebe Rock looking down&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s really the only cool thing we’ve done this month, but hopefully there will be more! The hot season is apparently going to be cooling off in the near future which will make it easier to enjoy the outdoors, at least until it gets cold! We still have several game preserves to go to that we can’t miss!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/IMG_20200104_085241.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking across from Sibebe Rock. We&amp;amp;#8217;re at the highest point&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m grateful that we have a great group of fellow volunteers who enjoy doing fun things! Trying to find our way around can be daunting, so it’s nice to be able to go with volunteers who have knowledge of a place or better understanding of how to go places. Since we can’t drive (Peace Corps Eswatini rule), we generally know the area where we live. Having a larger group makes these fun adventures possible!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 06:06:48 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/january-in-eswatini</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/january-in-eswatini</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Kancane kancane (little by little)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been awhile since our last post. Any activity that relies on the internet is a challenge. This evening I need to study Siswati so I decided to go ahead and roll the blogging and the studying together.  For once the internet connection seems to be holding steady.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spring has arrived and we no longer need to wear layers of pajamas under layers of blankets at night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20191012_173318.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Little herbs growing in the landlords’ garden. The garden, and the path to the garden, are new and under construction.*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20191012_180632-469x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*This is a park somewhat nearby.&amp;amp;nbsp; I was amazed by the color of the flowers on these beautiful trees.*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Night = kuhlwile (The “ku” sounds like “goo” and the “hl” is a cat hissing sound that you make by putting the tip of your tongue behind your teeth and letting air flow between your cheeks and tongue.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190813_175633-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Night view looking down towards Mbabane&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ulelenjani? = How did you sleep? Ngilele kahle = I slept well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, the weather has been sunny and comfortable. Lilanga = sun (it also means day). We have had a few days that have gotten really hot (kuyashisa) followed by impressive thunderstorms (liyadvuma) and rain (imvula).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get up early and make breakfast. I have been having porridge made from sorghum (emabele) with peaches (emampentjisi).  Then we walk down the hill to work.  A couple of industrious locals come by the office to sell boiled peanuts in the shell (ematongomane), boiled corn on the cob (umbile), and avocados (emakotapeni) around noon for everyone who forgot to pack a lunch. “Ema” is a prefix indicating multiple of something so when you buy just one avocado it’s just &lt;em&gt;li&lt;/em&gt;kotapeni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, we follow the guidance of our boss (mphatsi) so that we can better understand the needs of the citizens (nine bekunene) of Eswatini. We are staying very busy with the project. Ngimatasatasa = I am busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20191012_174403-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Okay, well maybe not as busy as these ladies. They were both turbo-walking, one while breastfeeding and the other while balancing brooms on her head! Very impressive!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day we either walk about two blocks to visit the mothers (bomake) who sell fruits and vegetables in the stalls along the street, go a little further to the shopping center for last minute dinner items, or just head back up the path to our apartment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_130539.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;These aren&amp;amp;#8217;t actually vendors near where we work in the city, but the stalls are a similar setup.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20191008_172213.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Walking up the driveway to our apartment. Ours is actually behind the new unit (just completed!) that you see on the left.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this point in the day, I’m usually really hungry (ngilambile) and tired (ngidziniwe). There aren’t as many convenience foods here so we cook (pheka) every day (onkhe malanga) and always have a lot of dishes to wash. We also have to wash the produce carefully so our delicate American stomachs don’t end up in knots. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190928_172452-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;All clean!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes in the evenings I study (ngifundza) Siswati, but usually I just drink tea (nginatsa litiya) and read for awhile until I am sleepy (ngiyatela).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: the word kancane from the title is pronounced with the “c” as a click made by the tip of the tongue on the back of the front teeth. So it’s like gan-*click*-an-ay. The click is used is a lot of words, for example no (cha) and sorry (ncesi).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 16:08:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/kancane-kancane-little-by-little</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/kancane-kancane-little-by-little</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Kathmandu and Boudha Too</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The last three days have been a whirlwind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now proud residents of Boudhanath (“BOH-dah-nahth”), called Boudha (“BOH-dah”) for short. We’d imagined it as a separate town, but it’s really just a district of Kathmandu, just as bustling as the rest of the city. Also, we mistakenly thought it would be like a culturally distinct Tibet-town. Sure, you see more Buddhist monks and Tibetan signs here than elsewhere, but it still blends into the Hindu Nepali rest of the city. According to Dr. Barstow, it’s difficult to distinguish between the two cultures at all — Kathmandu has been a center of cultural exchange between India and Tibet for millennia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lemme try to paint a picture here. Narrow streets twist and turn around haphazardly constructed buildings. To navigate, you step over mud puddles, under low-hanging cables, and through gates. You’ll see some construction zones, because the 2015 earthquake left lasting damage. It’s monsoon season, which means that it rains torrentially for a few hours each day, so you’ll want to duck under concrete shop awnings for cover. Watch out for taxis, cars, and especially motorcycles! They’ll speed around blind corners, honking to tell you to get out of the way. You’re bound to bump into some fellow pedestrians, but they’re used to it; no need to say “excuse me”. Several stories of tiny shops, each packed with goods, line the road. Most seem to specialize in one thing: fruit, soap, space heaters, you name it. My favorites so far are tailor shops — they’ll sew you whatever you like from the beautiful rainbows of fabric stacked from the floor to the ceiling. Boudha is centered around its famous stupa, one of the largest in the world. To show respect, always walk clockwise around it. In the touristy area around the stupa, you’ll see Buddhist statues, Buddhist prayer beads, and souvenir T-shirts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3838-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to write specialized blog posts soon about food, animals, Rangjung Yeshe, local religion, and such. I’d like to remember the first things we did here, though, so here’s a quick chronological rundown of our first few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ate breakfast at Shechen Guest House with the group (plus a lovely Indian-Australian family we made friends with at the airport), then headed out right away to see Boudha for the first time. We spent an hour or two crowded into a closet-sized enclosure of ATM machines and walking back and forth between a photocopy shop and a Ncell (Nepali cell service) shop to get SIM cards. To get there, we had to cross the main road for the first time — quite the exciting experience when there are practically no traffic laws! Then, we visited the Western-style coffee shop and went to my now-favorite restaurant for lunch. In the afternoon, we spent a few hours at someone’s home. Megan, a student who participated in this same program last year, is house-sitting there and taking care of the kitten, Rigpa. Dr. Barstow left so that Megan could tell us dirty secrets! (Spoiler: there are no dirty secrets unless you participate in the nightlife in the backpacker ghetto area of Kathmandu. Not our scene.) Finally, Megan, Mesa, Yuki, Gabriel, and I ate dinner at a Spanish restaurant with unimpressive food but an impressive view. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3849-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over breakfast at the guest house, Dr. Barstow proposed a relaxed itinerary for the day, but it quickly became apparent that his definition of “relaxed” is different from ours. We started by visiting our new school, Rangjung Yeshe. Unlike other monasteries tucked away into small spaces, this one has quite the large compound! We met one of Dr. Barstow’s close professor friends, the wonderfully caring student services coordinator (who Chökyi Nyima Rinpoche calls the “shedrub mama”), some monks, and even an administrator from Corvallis. We went along with Dr. Barstow to the quarters of a senior monk to have him fill a couple Tibetan statues with religious items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we kept walking… &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3852-1024x769.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and walking…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3857-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and walking… &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3860-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;until we reached a more rural area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3863-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had some well-deserved sodas from a corner store at the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3865-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worn out, we took taxis back to Boudha, recovered with a cold matcha latte and blended mocha at the Western coffee shop, rested at the hotel, went out to dinner, and picked up a few necessities (yay hand soap!) at one of the larger corner stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running out of time, so I’ll keep this short! We went on our biggest expedition yesterday. We took a long taxi ride across Kathmandu to Swayambhu, one of the holiest sites in Newar Buddhism. Boudha felt pretty urban, but the larger streets and crowds in the middle of Kathmandu set it apart. Dodging street dogs, adorable monkeys, and less-adorable pushy street vendors, we walked up many flights of stairs, observing all kinds of ancient art along the way. The top of the temple has so much history and significance that I feel terrible devoting so few words to it, but you can read more &lt;a href=&quot;http://swayambhu.buddhism-foundation.org/about/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3874-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3875-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3891.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lots of steps. Lots of statues with offerings. Lots of prayer flags.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3892.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lots of monkeys.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3888.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This is one of Dr. Barstow&amp;amp;#8217;s favorite Buddha statues in the world, so I took a picture.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our way back home, we stopped in Thamel, the backpacker ghetto area of town that Dr. Barstow can’t stand because of its extreme orientation toward foreigners. However, it has the best bookstores and restaurants, so we browsed his favorite bookstore in the world — I bought two books — and ate lunch at a large Western-style pizzeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in Boudha, we went to Fr. Greg’s home. He’s a Jesuit Catholic priest, longtime resident of Nepal, extremely knowledgeable anthropologist, American, and our academic advisor. I think he’s the first person we’ve visited who has a servant. This particular servant, Raju, is a friendly dude and an incredible cook! Over tea, Fr. Greg told us all about the sprawling Nepali bureaucracy. I don’t think it’s legal to publicly criticize the government, so I’ll stop there…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way home from dinner, Jesus, Gabriel, and I came across a large group of monks dancing in the dark at the Shechen monastery. It was mesmerizing. We sat and watched for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time for breakfast! Be back soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 02:03:56 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/kathmandu-and-boudha-too</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/kathmandu-and-boudha-too</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Last Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is our last full day in Oregon! Lilly has a training in Portland followed by a lunch, we’ll overnight at a friend’s house, and then leave tomorrow morning at 11:45. We said goodbye to my parents on Wednesday and now it’s our turn!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone that helped us clear our apartment! Lilly and I have decided that 3rd floor apartments are not so much fun to move out of. Things were rushed, but we love you all and couldn’t have done it without your help!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for those that were aware: Lilly’s surgery on Wednesday went ok and she’s been healing up well. She discovered she had a retinal tear in her left eye on Tuesday, they operated on Wednesday to spotweld the retina in place, and then she got to spend Thursday feeling like she’d been punched really hard in the face. Not the best timing in terms of us leaving the country, but at least her retina won’t detach in Japan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to be starting this journey and look forward to sharing lots of pictures and stories with everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190802_1155083832.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 13:47:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/last-day</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/last-day</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Life during pre-service training</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So it’s now Thursday. We’ve been in training since Monday, but in eSwatini since Friday or so. It’s been pretty intense overall. Our days are planned from 7am until 7pm. Breakfast, then language, then tea time, then a lecture followed by lunch. A few more lectures, then an off block (“wellness”) followed by supper at 6. Outside of hours, we are restricted to campus. We can’t drive, and we aren’t all that comfortable with transit yet. The surrounding area (not really a neighborhood) has a number of street vendors, but it’s not really a place to wander around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we took our first trip on the local transportation, the khumbi (koom-bee), where we needed to communicate in SiSwati to find the right ride, learn the price, pay, get off at the right spot, etc. Our language teachers accompanied us so we wouldn’t be completely terrified!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are very different from American buses! They drive past rather frequently and you need to hail them to stop, then make sure they are going where you want to go. There are places they tend to stop, but only the Swazis seem to understand where! You sit on a bench seat. It’s crowded, but only as much as there are seat belts. No standing since khumbis are really just passenger vans. Then the driver gets going to the destination. At some point, sometimes not until you get off, the conductor asks for the fare. The conductor accompanies the driver but sits with the passengers to answer questions, determine if there is space for another person, and handle money so the driver can drive. It’s all by hand, nothing electronic or computerized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ends of routes are usually the bus ranks. Think of a bus station, but then stop thinking of a bus station. It’s not really anything like that. A huge number of khumbis wait for people, their conductors calling out. It’s densely packed with people and vehicles trying to get where they need to be. Also lots of fruit and other vendors. Somehow it works out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A word on language… We understood that English was the official language so knowing the local language, SiSwati (a Zulu relative), was mostly for making a good impression. It turns out that SiSwati is still used quite a lot. People freely switch back and forth, and outside of offices, English is definitely second-class. It is true that, even in offices, being able to greet and introduce yourself in SiSwati is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of offices, we visited the official Peace Corps office in Mbabane today. It’s somehow part of the embassy, though a different building. Security to get in, phones left at the door, etc. Once inside though, it was a pleasant yard and a pretty normal office building. We went over some things and had another briefing. They take our safety and wellbeing very seriously so we talk about how it all works, our role, their role, etc. pretty often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more full day of training. We still have language Friday, Saturday, Sunday, and Monday, but after tomorrow much less lecture and more traveling/sightseeing/shopping. I’m looking forward to finally seeing our actual residence in Mbabane. We’ve met our counterparts at the Ministry of Health so we have an idea of how our project will go. We’re almost there!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 13:38:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/life-during-pre-service-training</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/life-during-pre-service-training</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Makhwapheni</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Makhwapheni (mock-wah-pay’-nee) – Temporary lover&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working hard alongside the Swazis the past almost 8 months to assist with building up their medical records system, the plug has been pulled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/03/MicrosoftTeams-image.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I think this picture says it all&amp;amp;#8230;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey has been hard at times. Coming as the latest in a line of various volunteers and other organizations, it’s hard to assure people that we are there to help and won’t just start some crazy new thing and then run off. Our focus has been to try to add features to their EMR (electronic medical records system) and update some of their processes to enable them to offer the care the population needs (by their invitation and working on their priorities). Coming from a different background, our experience includes things that haven’t been tried here so we worked to train/mentor local people so they would be able to utilize these techniques for the long haul. The Peace Corps’ definition of success includes leaving an organization in a state that they don’t need you anymore. If we can’t leave without things falling apart, we’ve failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Makhwapheni (from the post heading) apparently means “temporary lover.” There are always (in every environment) people who are resistant to change, looking for a reason to discount new ideas. Makhwapheni implies that since we’re just the most recent in a string of “lovers,” we don’t need to be taken seriously. This general idea also leads to questions about extending our time to get more done. At this point, we weren’t really interested in extending though since the goal was to pass along knowledge and perspective, then get back to family and friends. Now it’s out of our hands regardless and we can’t even finish our commitment. That’s really the worst possible case since we weren’t able to get things to the point of hand-off, and it basically validates their initial worries. It’s all kind of surreal at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll write another post soon with more details. At the moment we don’t have any more information to give. Volunteers are all waiting at their posts for further instructions, packing and reflecting. Stay tuned…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 04:08:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/makhwapheni</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/makhwapheni</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Manga – まんが</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Those of my family and friends that know me well know that I’ve always been an avid reader. Devouring all of the fantasy and sci-fi novels I could get my hands on from the age of ten, I’ve built up quite a hefty collection of books that I now have to lug along wherever I move. Not content with the cold touch of an e-book, I’ve always preferred to read physical copies of all of my favorite books. I’ve read my first copy of Eragon, my all time favorite book, so many times I had to buy a second copy because the first is literally falling apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noticeably absent from my voluminous collection, however, is even a single volume of manga. For those who are as yet unaware, manga is a Japanese style of graphic novel. Manga is a term that covers all ranges of fiction genres, and I’m sure some non fiction as well. I discovered manga in middle school while working as a library assistant, and I’ve loved the medium ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many graphic novels, a single series of manga can span anywhere from 2 volumes to 100. This is in part because manga are also serialized, meaning one chapter is released regularly and compiled into a volume later. The longest running manga will typically run around 300 chapters, though there are those that have topped 1000. In order to have the complete series of a manga, one would need to buy all the volumes, or all of the copies of the serialized version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where tragedy strikes. In the United States, not only are manga difficult to find in English, let alone Japanese, but they’re also rather expensive. $4-8 a volume doesn’t sound like much until you need to buy 27 of them! When you can buy normal print books for $20 ish dollars new, why would you buy a used set of manga for more than $100? As such, I’ve only ever owned 5 or 10 volumes of manga, and never a complete series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190913_2153541693822045367090299.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;88 volumes of manga&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, in Japan, manga are very common and used goods are rather cheap. Today, Damian and I decided to go by a used book store on a whim after dinner, just to see what was on offer. They were having an absolutely ridiculous sale, where all manga currently priced at ¥50 ($0.50) were marked down to ¥10. Yes, that’s right. Roughly equivalent to $0.10 per volume. %0.025 of the price of a single used volume in English in the States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went a bit nuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did buy a few more normally priced volumes, around ¥100, but this sale was targeted directly at me, and I embraced it. In total I bought &lt;strong&gt;88 volumes&lt;/strong&gt; of manga. The cost of all 88 volumes came out to be about $30, or ¥3000. 88 volumes for $30. In the States, at the used price of $4 per volume, I would have spent $352.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how else to describe my current state of mind other than elated, but a picture is worth a thousand words, so I’ll wrap this up with one. Now I just need to figure out how to get all of these home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_p20190913_2159210347385018976424690030.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Manga in bags in our hallway&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 19:12:51 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/manga-%25e3%2581%25be%25e3%2582%2593%25e3%2581%258c</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/manga-%25e3%2581%25be%25e3%2582%2593%25e3%2581%258c</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>My first day at work, 最初の日</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was my first day at school! Class hasn’t actually started yet for students, but teachers continue to go to school and do administrative work and the like through most of the summer break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main, or “base”, school is called Minamikata Elementary School (南方小学校). There are 16 teachers including office staff and administrators. There’s one teacher for each grade, 1-6, who teach all subjects. There are two teachers for special needs students. There’s also a school nurse and a teaching assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone at Minamikata was extremely welcoming and helpful the entire day. I spent the first hour or so chatting with the principal and vice principal and getting an introduction to the school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have my own desk in the teacher’s room. In Japanese schools, the teachers move from room to room and the students stay in one place. As such, all teachers have their desks in one office instead of having desks in each classroom. Teachers spend most of their time in this room when students are on break. There were some students at school today, but only for club activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the teachers at my school don’t really speak English. My Japanese isn’t amazing right now, but I’m sure after even a couple of weeks it will improve quite a bit simply from necessity! Nonetheless, I had a good time talking with the teachers and both asking and answering questions. I also had the opportunity to prepare for class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, after I showed an interest in sitting in on the kanji classes taught in the school to improve my own Japanese, one of the teachers brought me copies for the workbooks the students use. She also was so kind as to check my work after I finished each section, which was fun for both of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I had a good first day, and I’m looking forward to the coming year. I’ll be posting photos once I’ve confirmed what is and is not ok to post online with my principal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 03:30:44 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/my-first-day-at-work-%25e6%259c%2580%25e5%2588%259d%25e3%2581%25ae%25e6%2597%25a5</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/my-first-day-at-work-%25e6%259c%2580%25e5%2588%259d%25e3%2581%25ae%25e6%2597%25a5</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>On our way!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/08/IMG_20190801_160906__01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;It&amp;amp;#8217;s HOT in Atlanta!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sleeping for two hours, we boarded the shuttle from Corvallis to the airport, then took the 8am flight to Atlanta. Now we’re laying over waiting for the trip to Johannesburg. Finishing the final tasks of packing our luggage, packing up the house, and general house cleaning seemed like it would never be done! Then, actually walking out for the last time (after 10:00), the doors locked behind us, I think we all felt it more than we thought we would. Ten years in a house is a long time, especially when it’s your home from middle/high school up to marriage (as kids and as parents of those kids). It’s not just a house, of course, it’s a home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was tough as parents needing to focus on our own departure to the exclusion of helping the boys with theirs. One the one hand, it’s good that we all depart so close, but it feels like we parents should be there to see the kids off first. We know they’ll do great once they are there, but the lead-up can be stressful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we work on cramming a little more on SiSwati language learning. I don’t think we’ll be impressing anyone with our vocabulary, but we don’t want to be completely unprepared! The first two weeks consist of daily Peace Corps classes about the country, the people, the language, and hopefully our actual assignments! We’ve already done a number of hours of videos and assignments about the organization and what it means to be part of it. We aren’t too worried. We trust that between Peace Corps and God, we’ll be taken care of! One day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 14:34:51 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/on-our-way</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/on-our-way</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>One-third down!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I type this, it’s Sunday evening. It’s been a sweltering hot last few days with temperatures up into the 90’s, with some areas (what they call the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Veld&quot;&gt;lowveld&lt;/a&gt;) over 100℉! The next few days promise more heat until Wednesday when it suddenly drops a ridiculous 40°. We are expecting some rough weather, likely hailstorms again. Just when we thought we were done with hail!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/image.png&quot; alt=&quot;Crazy weather we&amp;amp;#8217;re having&amp;amp;#8230;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we started August 1*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/tsb_PPFW1jQIsLTgzR_4AJz7FJVK07HR1yc4QuKqtRq1tcyrW3aHPGv61uruCVZ9EvUaRqZo0AlS0_-EL3vQ7iglCZazro58suTonM3kddJ1tf1ZWRUHUm5sIKxI9L7VvcCNwxzzO0mpqJ1BvF8GYd3KMBIBFwfbrMR1CJEm3UNKR4FE7DU3GaymCcl2utzAYt6hn-q41JD-3dsOLXWdOM4R5JIqZ9vz-Ja-MY8jlBrfzsB8hNh3SnFDbcR3v-JihBNzlTI5RTmhjYD2Mb9nesesGEy3euNfFbx6zALycVNcOxriamGNkOiCGezlndL_8WfLw6wXc-NXfq78mVeLsu1I68hjR3LgH3BLCMlDFaoIg1RcdYbFwl3P-f-r2j1swD3ISSsF1so4TzA8H1K-7sHnbE_aHGvi_XwICDkdG4bSbmats5hctzvDnf3hO55Eysxt_enhtZzM60NYvWC5PxstyFWn6ZI9jIplJlCWWS77Hgezz8abU0F8GKdizWcKV_nhQDr3QxCg4m2zV4dtkFp_8nqxB3D9EL1UNeHnDHoVtEWRpVTHf-etHhP-Pprwg9_zIRgSZDhXVIxGUB3KXxl8OJjnMCc7LMfOPh75jAWYttYL5fEO9Y6paCyppcdle_SCRYGD4VfOXWGheMj20fqVZGwgSJ8a2dI7iFpmiU7fLHqyxg=w724-h965-no&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
Last week, we spent a few days at the Peace Corps training campus (actually local school that lets them use it) for Thanksgiving. Volunteers don’t often get together formally, other than sometimes for the swearing-in of new groups, so some of the time was mandatory. We had some talks about being effective, new or revised policies and procedures, and some peer sessions where people talked about their projects or lessons learned. On Thursday, we spent about half the day at the country director’s house. It was a beautiful home and there was an enormous spread of food! The whole time was great for reconnecting with people, making new friends, and strengthening ties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent-jnb1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/s960x960/77071672_2682966401749861_4157848339066388480_o.jpg?_nc_cat=111&amp;amp;_nc_ohc=Jpi-jevRVmIAQlIho68WDMVON_KwBf5DL5w71Mj0Vr6dQLLIlRCIaPZrA&amp;amp;_nc_ht=scontent-jnb1-1.xx&amp;amp;oh=9520385ae26cbd6a2bbf968704e61ed0&amp;amp;oe=5E75A1E3&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
In just over two weeks, we’ll be going to Japan to meet Damian and Lilly, and a few days later, Gabriel and Kendrea will be arriving! G&amp;amp;K will be finished with their semester abroad and heading home. We’re so excited that we can all meet up in the same place! We’ve been having weekly video calls, but it’s never the same. Often, the bandwidth here or in Nepal just isn’t conducive to a good connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week should be a good one. We are preparing to put out our second software release, and drawing up plans for the post-JAD updates. It’s a lot of work, and no small amount of pressure to get things right. We are looking forward to the challenge though!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 12:50:45 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/one-third-down</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/one-third-down</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Orthodox Church in Japan – Pt. 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This first post is going to be an introduction to the churches in our area. I think this will probably end up being a series of posts because there’s a lot to share. Keep an eye out for some more posts with more artists of the Church here covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been about a month now and we’ve finally managed to make it to all of the churches in the area. The first liturgy we went to was in Ishinomaki, which is a bit of a drive south of us but isn’t too bad. We tried to avoid toll ways and ended up taking a longer route than necessary as the road we thought had a toll ended up not, so it’s about a 25-30 min drive normally. For our first visits, we tried to arrive a bit early to give us a chance to meet some of the parishioners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father Luke (神父のルカ 田畑 隆平) has been very understanding of our situation and his English is good enough to convey important information. He’s asked me to read hours in English before liturgy at most parishes, which was interesting. The singing is also interesting at an the parishes, it’s all from the heart, but also unison, slow, and on a collection of pitches. Everywhere has been thrilled to have some new singers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that note, Father has 5 churches in the surrounding area: Ishinomaki, Kurihara, Takashimizu, Sanuma, and a few more. They’re all within a 30 min drive from us, so nothing too terrible, and they all have very small congregations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ishinomaki – 石巻&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190901_091107179_HDR-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The font of St. John the Theologian in Ishinomaki&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The church in Ishinomaki has some interesting history attached to it. The original building is still standing but is not being used as the church building anymore because the state took control of it. It’s currently a museum and is the oldest standing Christian church in Japan. We’ll go there at some point and take some pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The size of the congregations here is quite different from what we get in the US. Many Japanese people, even to this day, do not have cars so most parishioners walk to church. Very often the only cars in the lot are Father’s and ours. As such, 5 people seems be a rough average with some parishes being much smaller and some being a bit bigger. Obviously Tokyo, Sendai, and the other large cities have larger congregations but they also have transit systems so….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190901_092451437.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Interior of St. John the Theologian. The iconostasis is quite old and the iconography shows some age. Still very pretty though!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sanuma (in Tome) – 佐沼&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190819_132117676-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Church in Sanuma, they like the grape pattern I guess. Church of the Transfiguration&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our first visit to Ishinomaki, we were told there was vigil at 10a in Sanuma (our town), which I planned on attending. Lilly was in Sendai for JET stuff, so I walked the 17 min to get there alone. Once there it quickly became clear that it was actually liturgy, so that was a fun realization. Since the congregation here was 2-3 people, Father had to lead the choir as well as do everything else. He refuses to allow me to serve because, “no one ever serves at these parishes”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This church was definitely the smallest I’ve been to, but the building is still large enough to accommodate a decent number of people. It’s possible that the small turnout was because it was a weekday liturgy or because it was firing the week of Oban (a family holiday). The next Sunday liturgy here is the end of the month, so we’ll see then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There doesn’t seem to always be a meal afterward services. Some places have, others haven’t. Sanuma did have a meal afterwards, someone walked to the 7-11 nearby and grabbed box lunches for us, as well as mugicha (麦茶), or roasted barley tea, and some desserts. I got to talk with Father for a bit and learned more about orthodoxy in Japan as well as more info on the other churches he serves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Takashimizu (in Kurihara) – 高清水&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190825_120847282_HDR-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The exterior of the Church of the Transfiguration in Takashimizu, someone biked&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This church is smaller than Ishnomaki, but larger than ours in town. The building is still the only one we’ve seen not purpose built to be a church: it was clearly a house at some point that was gutted and converted. That said, it’s still nice inside and is the only place with all tatami floors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This church is nestled into a small village kinda in the mountains a bit, so the town itself was tiny. It also only has one emergency radio broadcast tower, which is apparently right next to the church, and they decided to test it as I was reading post-communion prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wakuya – 涌谷&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190908_115957222_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My lovely wife and the exterior of the church of St. Isaiah in Wakuya&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the largest church in Father’s area. You know it’s large because it has two readers and an alter server (his boy is too young without someone helping him). It’s also on a larger road and the doors of the church open right onto the sidewalk which probably helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the service, we went over to the hall and had a meal. This meal was actually more of a potluck, there were pickles, a seafood salad with tiny fish, and some other things that parishioners brought. Afterwards Father led a choir practice for the congregation on tone 8 (what they would be singing in a few weeks when the next liturgy happened there). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190908_115939592.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Walking into the church, Matushka is peaking out on the right&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, going back to our time in Tokyo. I did get to go visit Nikolaido (Holy Resurrection Cathedral), but considering the length of this post, I think I’ll make another one to cover that. I also wasn’t able to make it to a service, so I’ll have more to say later!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I’ll try to watch comments better, so if there’s anything people are curious about feel free to ask!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 19:56:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/orthodox-church-in-japan-pt-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/orthodox-church-in-japan-pt-1</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Orthodox Church in Japan – Pt. 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 15th, we were invited, along with a lot of other people from the area, to the consecration of St. John the Forerunner in Nakanida. Unfortunately, this was the first consecration I’ve been to, and my liturgical Japanese is… lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190915_125423658_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The exterior of the new building as seen from their hall&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The building was pretty darn full when we arrived, there were probably about 100 people there. This event had been announced all over the area so we drove an hour and there were definitely people that came from farther. There was also the choir from Sendai which came to sing and we really appreciated them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concelebrating was His Eminence, Bishop Seraphim of Sendai, 5 priests from the area including our Father Luke, the protodeacon from Sendai, and a collection of alter servers (no subdeacons though). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190915_093002548.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Right after the bishop entered the building, everyone walked to the front and they sang a bunch of stuff. *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a whole lot of stuff going on that neither Lilly nor I could understand, but there were several parts of the consecration service that we still managed to figure out! The first was when all of a sudden there was a lot of very loud banging from behind the alter, then the bishop opened the beautiful gates wearing an apron over his robes and you could see the wooden structure of the alter being assembled. I couldn’t quite get a picture of it since I didn’t know it was coming ☹️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190915_103105519_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Things happening at the doors to the church.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the consecration was done, they launched into liturgy which was our first hierarchical service here. Things went pretty much as expected, though it was fun to see everything in Japanese with so many clergy. We’ve definitely gotten used to small, intimate services during our time here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/download_20190923_132255-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eagle rug&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190915_110819576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The protodeacon wrangling the oversized gospel.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190915_112407859.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eis pola eti déspota!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, agreed the service was done, everyone went outside and took a picture of everyone in front of the new church. After that, we ask headed over to a banquet at a nearby hotel where we were fed some pretty yummy food and listened to lots of speeches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the banquet we talked to some Russian ladies that were all excited to talk to the young Russian family that had showed up. Unfortunately for them, neither of us knows Russian, so they were a bit sad and surprised. One of them spoke English though and we talked for a bit. We made some friends from the Sendai area!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190915_132333427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The hall we ate in and listened to speeches in&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also got to talk to a French dude who worked on the iconostasis. Apparently a Japanese-French dude started a carpentry shop after moving to Japan from France. He then attracted some French people that wanted to learn Japanese carpentry and they work mostly on shrines. When they heard there was an Orthodox church starting in town, they wanted to take the job. The guy said that it was a really fun job, that they all really enjoyed making the iconostasis, and that they hoped they would get the opportunity to work on Orthodox churches again in the future. He also said that they used many, many different kinds of Japanese woods to make iconostasis and that it was fun to weave Japanese culture and orthodoxy together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190915_115426672.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A somewhat cleaner view of the iconostasis&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:52:51 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/orthodox-church-in-japan-pt-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/orthodox-church-in-japan-pt-2</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Blog Post</title>
        <description></description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 20:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/page</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/page</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Rangjung Yeshe Orientation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last week we’ve been attending various events at Rangjung Yeshe Institute orientation. I should prolly start with some background info about the school:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rangjung Yeshe Institute (RYI) operates inside a Buddhist monastery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The monastery is named “Ka-Nying Shedrub Ling”, but most locals know it as “The White Monastery”.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Ka-Nying” stands for Kagyu and Nyingma, which are two of the four major lineages of Tibetan Buddhism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Shedrub” means monks can take classes there, kind of like seminary (more on this shortly).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The monastery is in Boudhanath, a Tibetan neighborhood of Kathmandu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kathmandu University (KU) and RYI work together to offer credit for classes at RYI. This agreement is how we get OSU credit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RYI and KU operate on the semester schedule, so a full course load of 16 semester credits gets us 22.5 term credits back at home. This means we can drop a class while still keeping our credits per term above the scholarship threshold. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190819_102412.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;See? It&amp;amp;#8217;s white. Home to around 500 monks.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scholastic work for monastics is done at a “shedrub” (remember that that’s in the monastery name). We do classes at RYI, which gives Western-compatible credits (through KU) for Western- and shedrub-style classes. We will be taking one such shedrub-style class from a Khenpo, the monastic scholar equivalent of a doctorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all the classes are taught in English; Khenpo classes have Tibetan instructors and therefore a translator, but some higher-level Khenpo classes don’t have translators!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190822_092645.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;You can see the raised platform for the Khenpo to sit on, and the adjacent pad on the floor for the translator.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for actual information about the orientation! There are around 40 of us newcomers, and we attended many information sessions about food/water safety, earthquake preparedness, who to talk to if we’re stressed, proper etiquette for monastery and academic settings, etc. We also took prep classes in either Nepali or Tibetan. We chose Nepali, since that’s what our host family speaks. Overall, RYI offers language courses in Nepali, classical Tibetan, colloquial Tibetan, and Sanskrit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our classmates are ridiculously diverse. We’ve already made friends with people from Germany, Tibet, Finland, Argentina, Ecuador, Korea, Mexico, India, and Netherlands! Most people are around our age, but there are maybe 5 or 10 older people in their 40s-60s. There are also a few monks and nuns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/d5c8406b-778b-47d6-b77e-e0da0faf062c-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Another bonus: epic views of the Himalayan foothills!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One very comforting thing about RYI is that you take off your shoes before entering classrooms, offices, or the library. There are shelves outside each door where you put your shoes. Also, many of the classrooms don’t have chairs, so you sit on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190819_103310.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The wooden benches are not to be sat upon or even stepped over, since they&amp;amp;#8217;re used for studying religious texts.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the orientation lunches were provided at the monastery-owned Utpala Café, a short walk from the part of campus with classes. Being part of a monastery that does outreach to help all sentient beings, it should be no surprise that their whole menu is at least vegetarian, and whatever isn’t vegan can be easily substituted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3898.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_3904.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this four-day weekend, we will start classes for real on Monday. Here’s what we’ll be taking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are both taking:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buddhist Traditions: History and Culture 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buddhist Philosophy and Hermeneutics (taught by a Khenpo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nepali 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kendrea is taking Buddhist Ethics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gabriel is taking Anthropological Study of Nepalese Religions (taught by Fr. Greg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 04:00:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/rangjung-yeshe-orientation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/rangjung-yeshe-orientation</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Reading Week and Dashain</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re wrapping up Reading Week, which is a week off of school that coincides with the 10-day celebration of the largest Hindu holiday: Dashain. As spelled in Nepali, is should be pronounced DAH-saii with the the “ii” pronounced nasally, but the “Dashain” transliteration is pervasive. Nepalis (very confusingly) swap “s” and “sh” all the time, and transliterating the nasal is often done by adding “-n” or “-ng”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the school is affiliated with a Buddhist monastery, we still get the week off; This is similar to Americans getting winter break, regardless of religion. There are some Hindus working and studying at the school, so it wouldn’t be fair to them! Plus the semester is long and we need a break; why not make the break and the holiday line up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dashain is the time of year for visiting family, feasting, swinging on bamboo swings, flying kites, worshiping, and offering animal sacrifices. For us, this means the businesses are closed, the transit is busy, there are occasional headless goats on the sidewalk, family members visit (we were never introduced), there are animal guts on the kitchen floor, and we get a blessing from our elder, the grandma of the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/59220774759__6c71e8b8-0450-4ff9-bd52-3e323c210dcb-e1571860050857-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Orthodox Christian wedding rings, Buddhist sacred thread from the nunnery, and Hindu tikka+grass+money+apple… we’re just getting showered with blessings!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4262-e1571860031248-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*We got to try out a Dashain swing! Note that the bamboo plants are firmly planted in the ground, so the swing can be deconstructed and reconstructed from the same living plants next year.*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technology Troubles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kendrea and I had tech issues within what felt like 5 minutes. Her laptop wouldn’t turn on and my phone wouldn’t stop turning on (boot loop). Both without provocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the laptop, she was only really missing a few weeks of notes, since they hadn’t synced in a while. We went to a repair place in a fancy part of Kathmandu, and it turns out there was a screen recall! If that’s the issue (and it seems to be), the repair is free. We just have to wait two weeks for the part to ship from Singapore… Thankfully we had the opportunity to use a temporary workaround and get the screen working at the repair shop, so she synced her notes to her phone and we aren’t down any files. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4388.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*On the way to the repair place, we came across this arch. Xi Jinping came to visit a couple days ago — he’s the first Chinese leader to visit Nepal since 1996. We were probably only a couple miles away from him. The countries’ relationship is fascinating, we’re worried on behalf of the Tibetan refugees in our community, and we’ll leave it at that.*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My phone has had an odd issue for a while where the backup/recovery utility can’t decrypt it, but the normal boot process still works. I had shrugged this off after little pursuit, but now I think I shouldn’t have. While unable to boot the main system, I was still able to boot into the backup/recovery utility. From here I did a full backup to a flash drive and reinstalled the operating system. I took the opportunity to install something other than what I had before, though, so I can proudly say that the only smidgen of Google code I’m running is sandboxed and unprivileged; everything else is open source!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, because of the weird encryption issue, I’m not sure if I’ll be able to actually access that backup. I haven’t put much effort in yet, but there’s a chance I lost everything. And by “everything” I really just mean mostly pictures. And by “pictures” I really just mean mostly memes. So not a big loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trekking to Nagi Gompa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From our front door, we took an 11-mile (horizontally measured) hike halfway up the nearest foothill (2300 ft. elevation gain) to a Buddhist nunnery, run by Chokyi Nyima Rinpoche, that we can see from our rooftop. It was exhausting, the views were great, the clean air was a nice break, and here are a bunch of pictures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/18d595b6-131e-43bc-bfda-91c1087ac38c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A super Nepali scene: flag, motorcycle, Dashain swing. A temple and bodhi tree (the same species as the tree the Buddha gained enlightenment under) are just out of frame. We could see lots of hills around Kathmandu Valley, several religious buildings on the hillside, and even the stupa and RYI. However, we’ll need to go in search of Himalayan peak views some other time.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4294.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sorry, most of the nunnery photos are currently inaccessible because of my phone.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4299.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;It was wonderful to see rural landscapes for a change!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4309-e1571860004918-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Did we mention it was pretty?*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We trekked with three other people. Sameer led the trip; he’s an upperclassman from India who happens to be Kendrea’s peer advisor. We got to know Tia in swing club, choir, and class; she already professionally translates between Hindi and English, and she’s here to learn to translate Tibetan and Sanskrit. Yuki is another OSU study abroad student, and we’ve really enjoyed getting to know her well here. Between the five of us, we used seven languages over the course of the trek: English, Hindi, Nepali, French, Japanese, Tibetan, and German. We spoke English and Hindi between us, and all the others with passersby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4247-e1571859987516-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Yuki, Sameer, Tia, and Gabriel in an awesome corridor formed by a mossy wall and a bamboo grove*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we hiked through the tangle of prayer flags, I wondered aloud how they get put up: “Maybe they tie a rock to the end and throw it. Or maybe they pay kids to climb the trees.” Naturally, we shortly came across a Tibetan family trying to hang up some prayer flags. They had tied a rock to the end and were trying to throw it. Then (as our Tibetan-speaking group members told us), they recruited a child to climb the tree, offering to pay him. We later joked about how I speak and whatever I say comes to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4266-e1571859944845-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*The aforementioned Tibetan family hanging up prayer flags*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the top, we came across a crystal clear stream that crossed the path. We used our water filter (thank you Stig and family!) to refill the water bottle and couldn’t help but realize that this is exactly the advertised use-case: encountering a beautiful Himalayan stream while trekking and low on water and wishing that there was a way to drink it safely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4274-e1571951415476-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*This monkey followed us for quite some time. I grabbed a rock just in case we needed to defend ourselves.*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4313-e1571859966488-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Beautifully lit views helped us get through the last few miles*.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Helping Classmates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the resident computer science students, we had no idea how useful our skills would be. For Khenpo class (the one taught in the traditional Tibetan monastic style), we need to memorize 15 verses, 10 of which (at random) we will need to recite for the test. To aid in the memorization process, I made a small terminal program in under 100 lines of C. After showing it to classmate, they wanted to use it! Knowing that a terminal-run program is hardly the most intuitive UI paradigm for this crowd, we set out to re-make it as a website. Another night or two later and the teacher forwarded the link to the class. &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.engr.oregonstate.edu/~kulpga/verses/&quot;&gt;Here it is&lt;/a&gt;, if you’re curious. Judging by the thankful emails, texts, and even in-person comments we’ve received, all before classes have even started up again, it seems that the memorization tool has been helpful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_4409.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 08:39:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/reading-week-and-dashain</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/reading-week-and-dashain</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <description></description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:57:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/search</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/search</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Seminar Break</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written on December 1. We’ve had some technical difficulties. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We just wrapped up a 12-day break from school to allow students to attend Chökyi Nyima Rinpoche’s seminar. Wow, what an amazing set of activities we had planned for the break! We were going to attend some of the seminar, participate in a tea ceremony at a Taiwanese restaurant by the stupa, go on a three-day getaway to a Himalayan village, attend a town hall for American citizens at the ambassador’s house, get all of our errands done…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…yeah, actually we got sick and stayed inside all day, except for brief excursions to the pharmacy to get decongestant and pain pills. Sigh. At least we had time to be productive (and not just in terms of mucus quantity).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a little news, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re back in choir! We’d quit because rehearsals were at an inconvenient time for us. Last Sunday, we taught swing class as usual, and both choir directors came. After class, they pulled us aside and basically said “hey, uh, we had a rough rehearsal last week and we could really use your voices”. We couldn’t say no to that—we can manage to attend just a couple inconveniently timed rehearsals. So, later that week, we bundled up, showed up to the dress rehearsal at the lovely monastery-run outdoor cafe where we usually eat lunch, grabbed some music binders, and sight-read our way through. It felt great to sing in a group again—plus, we got to skip the messy learning process!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG-20191211-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a lovely Thanksgiving dinner with a couple dozen other Americans at Fr. Greg’s house. We’d planned to cook a green bean casserole (heavily accommodated to fit the ingredients available here), but then we noticed that the recipe said to bake the casserole. We have no oven. Okay, green bean stir-fry it was! To our pleasant surprise, almost every dish was vegan, so we feasted well. There were even deep-fried Oreos. We met some new people and had some great conversations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG-20191211-WA0001-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG-20191211-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, we managed to spend Saturday night in the nearby Himalayan village of Nagarkot! More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 02:55:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/seminar-break</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/seminar-break</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Sendai – 仙台, Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_20191027_133825__012229661408174922187.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of a busy crossing in Sendai Sunday afternoon&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sendai! We haven’t talked much about this city, but it’s definitely the center of Miyagi. Sendai has a population of a bit more than a million people. It’s where you go for anything more than the basics, especially if you’re like us and find it hard to find that little piece of home. Sendai is where the only Costco in Miyagi lives, along with multitudes of other shopping locations, and a variety of specially shops not found elsewhere. Good examples of this are yarn shops, which are only available in Sendai. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/download_20191104_1616303805845721771386578.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The cathedral in Sendai, called a cathedral because this is the Bishop&amp;amp;#8217;s home base&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our little trip to Sendai, a bit more than an hour from Tome if you’re flush enough to take the toll road, started with a visit to the cathedral, as it was a Sunday morning. After finishing church, we decided to go see if we could find lunch nearby, and stumbled into a series of shopping streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_20191027_1246198454340763698829593.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view of one of the shopping streets we wandered down&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These avenues are basically like if an open air market grew up to be a shopping mall. There are entrances to the main streets periodically, and the streets are roofed with glass. Despite this it is very clear that you’re walking down a road between buildings, with those buildings frequently extending up past the glass canopy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_20191027_133451__01712438918916029930.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Shinto shrine directly off one of the shopping streets. Like a church in a mall, very surprising!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shops filling the street vary from hole in the wall ramen places to high tier luxury brands like Rolex and Gucci. There were also konbini (コンビニ), Japanese convenience stores, about once a block. One of the more interesting places we stopped by was a cat Cafe. It wasn’t what we expected, but it was a memorable experience none the less. My advice to anyone interested in visiting cat cafes is to do your research ahead if time, and that’s all I’ll say about it for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_20191027_125418135706407371417109.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Damian charming a couple residents of the cat cafe&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had lunch at a magical kind of restaurant, yakiniku (焼肉)! Order plates of thinly sliced raw mean and cook it yourself for the freshest of restaurant experiences. Some of them even have all you can eat buffet setups. Definitely a satisfying experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_20191027_1406102792442218105686376.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Damian grilling our lunch in the table&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch we headed over to the Sendai museum of History, where we got to see some historical artifacts important to the area, along with many, many maps. Honestly the museum almost deserves it’s own post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_20191027_1520568536494963660582638.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A truly huge original 200 ish year old map of Miyagi. Damian for scale.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were of course samurai artifacts, mainly related to Date Masamune, the much celebrated feudal Lord of Miyagi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_20191027_1539112470122748222334353.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Original armor worn by Date Masamune.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing so many old artifacts and clothing from Edo era Japan really impressed upon us how small most Japanese people used to be. It was fun taking pictures with Damian for scale!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_20191027_151827346550244051868466.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Period clothing, with Damian for scale.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a whole section of artifacts related to the voyage to Europe Date Masamune sent some of his samurai on. They sailed to Spain by way of Mexico in an attempt to open trade, with additional visits to the pope in Rome, but we’re unfortunately unsuccessful. Not long after Christianity was banned in Japan, so no further attempts were made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_20191027_1542127873158156895864187.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A replica of the ship they took to Mexico, the San Juan Bautista&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were also some related religious relics, as the voyage was guided by Spanish missionaries and Spain in the 1600s was very, very Catholic. They were very interesting to see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_20191027_1546224668817283837999110.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Catholic priests robes, ostensibly belonged to one of the missionaries, it maybe brought back from Rome&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final leg of our trip was the Sendai Aquarium, but since this post is getting a bit long I’ll leave that for another post!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 01:46:10 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/sendai-%25e4%25bb%2599%25e5%258f%25b0-part-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/sendai-%25e4%25bb%2599%25e5%258f%25b0-part-1</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Settling into the work routine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have been holding a number of meetings and working hard studying the source code for their systems while Karen is studying their business requirements and clinical environment. There is a large push to add some new features for HIV tracking so we need to ask a lot of questions and really understand what we’re doing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this acclimation, I’ve been to see two clinics: one run by the Red Cross, the other by the Salvation Army. It was surprising to see a chapel in the same building as the Salvation Army clinic, but Swazis are much more comfortable with religion not just being confined to church buildings. They even start many meetings with a prayer. So far they have been a generally humble and unassuming people who are very friendly and open about their beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190821_1511015025958697422394118.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Salvation Army clinic. The entrance is the large opening. Walking up the steps you can go straight into a chapel our go inside the clinic to the left.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clinics do standard vitals, immunizations, and exams, but they also proactively do HIV testing on everyone they can in other to get people in treatment and educate them on how to live with or avoid it. They have done a great job of reducing new infections through awareness campaigns and talking frankly about the risks of sexual activity. It’s been quite successful, but they continue to do everything they can to eradicate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190821_151353-12469269670772476461.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sorry for the bad shot. For comparison, E15 (Emalengeni) is currently about $1US.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each clinic has it’s own challenges with power and network connectivity. The systems deployed need to be resilient in addition to user-friendly and feature-packed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190821_155119-22432205469905824347.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fire instructions sign in the clinic, each rule in English and SiSwati.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our workplace, I sit in a shared office with another Peace Corps volunteer (Noah), a business analyst, and a empty desk people float to. Karen sits in a similar office with data management folks. Noah and I also have desks at the office for the international consulting firm FEI across the street. We go back and forth working with various people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190820_1707247257664253611293134.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Walking towards work. The Ministry office is on the left. Nando&amp;amp;#8217;s Chicken restaurant is on the right and has great food! Walking up the street further right past Nando&amp;amp;#8217;s is a building where our second office is (FEI).&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve gotten our SiSwati names given to us by our officemates! Since my name means “silver”in Welsh, I’m Ngcebo (the”c” is a click) which means precious (as in metal). Karen is Buhle which means beautiful lady!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190823_075408-17563788095262514534.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Assortment of animal skins sold outside of a traditional shop in the same building as our office.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to where we live, we can walk to work in about ten minutes but don’t actually pass many businesses. The building where we work houses a number of other government and NGO offices but not much commerce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190821_0757004954659555903845799.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lots of pickup trucks in the area, especially in the parking lot at work, have international partnership logos on them.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our way home, we pass a guy who sells roasted corn most days. It’s shucked and fire roasted which gives it a great flavor, though it’s much chewier than I’m used to corn being. The guy who sells it always gives us a big smile when we pass by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190823_075224-19116106513160940543.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kindling and firewood for roasted corn sold along the road. Quite yummy and inexpensive!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we turn to head up the very steep hill towards our place, there is an alcove at the base with carvings/sculptings of famous people. I believe it’s currently Nelson Mandela, Bob Marley, and their current ruler King Mswati III. It’s an interesting medium. He also makes dog houses and a few other items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190823_1513129019723461571637239.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Local man sculpting busts out of the hillside. I&amp;amp;#8217;m not sure why&amp;amp;#8230;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning (Saturday), we meet with another volunteer who has been working with Swazis running a program to introduce girls to STEM. Many of the rural schools don’t have any computers so the kids don’t even have mouse skills. The program starts with beginner computer concepts (turning it on, typing, mouse, windows, files) moves on to Microsoft Office, and even offers a game development class. Certificates are given for completion, and the kids work on a resume to showcase their new skills. Karen, Noah, and I are excited about helping where we can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190413_130059740614858071751986.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 11:48:07 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/settling-into-the-work-routine</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/settling-into-the-work-routine</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Shopping and culture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was a pretty slow day. After breakfast, we meet with the medical officers to go over anything they need to know for our stay. Of course, everything should be in our record, but data doesn’t necessarily seem to follow us as it should. At least it was painless enough.After that, we took a bus to a shopping area. This was important to get a feel for what’s available here and determine how hard it’s going to be to manage diet. It turns out, it probably some be very difficult. Selection of food was great and prices were reasonable. From peanut butter to burritos, spices to snacks, deodorant to soap, we’ll be able to get what we need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190804_1136445331442308867914590-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190804_1139016224722978377569512.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After our shopping trip, we went to a cultural village. This is setup like a traditional Swazi village from over 100 years ago. The village is actually the domain of one guy, along with his mother, his wives, his children, and dogs and cattle. Each hut is a bedroom, a brewing room, or other gathering room. A friendly guide showed us around and gave us the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190804_1448324249660331123109540-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190804_1441092769904818552443661.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the tour, we got to see a traditional dance as would have been performed by the single men and women. Their singing was amazing and the dancing quite lively. Not much relation to ballroom dance… &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190804_1549196530419875892053882.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190804_1521593043988112899009224.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that was done, we got back in our van. Right before getting in though, we saw a monkey nearby. It wasn’t the first, but it was the closest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190804_1600037375247594032695770.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back on campus, it’s rest and supper. Tomorrow starts the real work with our one-week training. No matter how challenging it is though, we can’t really complain. Regular Peace Corps pre-service training (PST) is three months!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:44:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/shopping-and-culture</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/shopping-and-culture</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Singapore to Kathmandu</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So first, there’s the Singapore airport. Stunning. Beautiful. Clean. You may have seen pictures of it before, but the largest indoor waterfall is inside a giant indoor rainforest in a glass dome. There’s also a walk-in butterfly garden and a koi pond. It’s just crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/08/IMG_20190817_125418.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Jewel of the Singapore airport&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had about 6½ hours between flights, so we (me, Kendrea, Mesa, Kalie, Dr. Barstow) decided to leave the airport! Immigration and customs was fairly quick, but there was definitely an authoritarian vibe…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/08/img_3816.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took a taxi to the famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gardens_by_the_Bay&quot;&gt;Gardens by the Bay&lt;/a&gt; and saw the weird &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marina_Bay_Sands&quot;&gt;Marina Bay Sands&lt;/a&gt; towers. Entrance to the Gardens is free, but you need to pay to enter some portions. It was too much money to enter the indoor greenhouses, but we did decide to do the hanging bridge in the Supertree Grove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/08/IMG_20190817_141521.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The plants are beautiful from above!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After marveling at the cleanliness of the Gardens, we took the subway to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raffles_Hotel&quot;&gt;Raffles Hotel&lt;/a&gt;. The whole subway experience was much closer to an airport tram than a US public transit vibe. We were shocked when we saw a single q-tip on the ground, since it was the only hint of litter. We ate some very good and cheap food at an underground food court, then headed up to Raffles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/08/IMG_20190817_153814.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Internal courtyard at Raffles&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried to go to the Long Bar to try a Singapore Sling (exclusive mixed drink), but the line was too long for how much layover we had left. Instead we went to a courtyard with a less-fancy bar and got some drinks there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/08/IMG_20190817_154310.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This was rather expensive&amp;amp;#8230;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/08/IMG_20190817_153809.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This is what an international booze collection looks like&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked a bit to find a taxi and returned to the airport. Everything went smoothly as we re-entered the airport, boarded the plane to Kathmandu, and left the ground one last time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kathmandu&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We landed at around 9pm local time and exited the plane straight to the tarmac. A bus came to pick us up and bring us to the terminal, where we filled out a form on a glitchy kiosk, paid the $125 visa fee, and went through customs (which was kind of a joke). It took us a while to all make it through the process, but when we finished, we got on a taxi and had the strangest transit experience yet. Kendrea made the mistake of using the bathroom in the airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/08/img_3820-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Inside was a squat toilet and no toilet paper.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we all reconvened after customs, we got on a taxi and had the strangest transit experience yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the roads here are dirt and not exactly flat. There are usually no lines on the road. You don’t need a license to drive. Most people don’t wear seatbelts, and some cars (like the taxi) have them inaccessible under the aftermarket seats. Over half of the vehicles are motorcycles. Many of the cars are manuals with small tires (so you feel the bumps more). There are dogs, people, and sometimes even goats and cows in the road. Instead of slowing down before going around a blind corner, people just honk to announce their presence. If someone is driving too slowly, they’ll get honked at when overtaken. It’s common to swerve into oncoming traffic to go around someone who’s slow, a sleeping dog, or a pothole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, the whole thing physically felt like a rollercoaster and emotionally was just a big game of trust. A taxi driver, of all people, should be pretty good at navigating the chaos, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at Shechen Guest House (where we’ll stay until we move in with our host families) after closing time, so we had to kind of holler at the gate for someone to come. We entered a courtyard and picked up our key, then went to our room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found two pretty normal-looking beds that turned out to not have normal mattresses. They’re basically mats rolled out on the bed frame, so they’re pretty firm. Comfy enough, but certainly not what we’re used to in the US. We took a cold shower and went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Sorry for the lack of Kathmandu pictures. It was dark and we were very tired. More pictures to come later!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 01:47:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/singapore-to-kathmandu</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/singapore-to-kathmandu</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Super Typhoon Hagibis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20191013_134323749_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rice fields across from our apartment on Sunday. These fields are always dry, so it was weird to look out and see a lake!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those that follow the news, you might have heard of the typhoon that slammed into Japan last weekend. The typhoon caused massive damage to certain parts of the country, killed a number of people, and caused flooding that lasted for quite a while. Thankfully, by the time the typhoon got to us, it had lost some of it’s oomph and we just got lots of rain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original predicted path for the Super Typhoon Hagibis had it hitting Tokyo and then sort of bouncing off and going back out to sea. That obviously didn’t happen though, and instead it hit Tokyo, went up the mainland, and back out to sea after hitting Hokkaido to the north. Though the path wasn’t what people were expecting, we still didn’t get hit very hard and only had minor flooding for a day or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20191013_135537881_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;One end of the parking lot at Daily Port, a grocery store we frequent.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said… people were definitely scared and we didn’t know what to expect. We kept getting emergency texts and emergency broadcast announcements (over loudspeakers) warning us that the conditions had gotten worse and that various nearby towns were either evacuating or opening shelters due to flooding. Not to mention that we live about 3 blocks from the river, so if the levees hadn’t held or hadn’t been high enough, we would have been in a world of hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/Screenshot_20191012-210853.png&quot; alt=&quot;One of the many emergency alerts we got.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did pack go backs and made sure to have some food, water, and clothing, as well as some books and stuff just in case we got the alert to evacuate, but it never came to that. As it started raining harder and harder, we walked down our covered stairs a few times and ran across the street to watch the water level rising. It was pretty incredible how quickly the water level rose in our little stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we decided to go to sleep for the night, it was a little concerning again because not all of our windows seal completely and though the wind wasn’t as bad as it could be, it was still stronger than it had been during our time here. We did see some water in the tracks of two of our windows in the evening, but by morning everything was still dry inside. Also, our screens blew around and made some noise, but again, nothing was damaged in the morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20191013_143039535_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Temporary barrier put across a walkway down to the river front. There&amp;amp;#8217;s usually a walking path down a ways and two long flights of stairs down to the river! We&amp;amp;#8217;ll try to get a good picture at some point when we&amp;amp;#8217;ve had some time to dry out so you can compare the river.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we emerged on Sunday morning after almost 12 hours of heavy rainfall. Our side of the river didn’t have much for flooding, we have more fields mixed in to the city to absorb water, but the other side didn’t fare as well. The river near us rose maybe 3-4 meters (3-4 yards) and Sanuma had lots of roads that were under about 8 cm (2-3 in) of water, though that didn’t stop traffic from continuing on through like normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20191013_135459850_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Very flooded road&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20191013_142612742.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Even more flooded road!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Church was cancelled in the town it was supposed to be in last weekend and was instead held in Ishinomaki. We weren’t sure we’d be able to make it since there are lots of sections that go through fields and we didn’t know how flooded it would be. Also, Google didn’t do a good job of staying up-to-date with road closures due to flooding, so we really had no idea if we could make it. As such we just stayed in our area and took pictures to show you guys, our awesome readers!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 07:46:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/super-typhoon-hagibis</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/super-typhoon-hagibis</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Swazi Fire!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/319027-Eswatini-Swazi-Kitchen-Swazi-Fire-Sauce-275g-new.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This was our first introduction to Swazi Fire. They served the hot sauce during our training week. It was sitting innocently at the end of the table in an unlabelled bowl. I thought to myself, I like salsa… Wow, nope! I quickly learned that they are not kidding around with their hot sauce! A tiny amount goes a long way!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190827_172139.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;There&amp;amp;#8217;s plenty of literal fires though too! They burn small areas to clear away the brush and reduce the chance of a bigger more dangerous fire.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/09/VID%5C_20190827%5C_172306.mp4&quot; alt=&quot;This fire started burning through the highway signposts!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190914_120623.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The plants seem pretty accustomed to the fires.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190914_120904-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;See? Happy new growth just in time for the start of the rainy season!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/MVIMG_20190914_121200-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;amp;#8230;the circle of liiiiife! ♪♪&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/downloadfile-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eswatini is also where the Kniphofia plant comes from. For those who don&amp;amp;#8217;t know, in Oregon people plant them in their flower gardens and call them Red Hot Pokers. Get it? It&amp;amp;#8217;s another type of Swazi Fire!!! 😅&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/MVIMG_20190915_174920.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This is not really on topic, but it&amp;amp;#8217;s a pretty flower that we see along the roadside on our walk to work. Also, it reminds me of a little flame. I don&amp;amp;#8217;t know the name though.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/MVIMG_20190910_174711.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Speaking of our walk to work, here is a picture looking out across the street from the building where I usually work.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/09/MVIMG_20190911_120233-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Last week one of our meetings was at the UN building. Arian was very flattered to be mistaken for 007!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/MVIMG_20190911_111404.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I was impressed by how cheerfully decorated the building is inside. It&amp;amp;#8217;s very different from the UN building in Geneva, Switzerland!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190909_135657-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Even the lizards are colorful here. These little guys with the turquoise blue heads are pretty common.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/09/MVIMG_20190914_172454-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Back at the office, here is a truck with the logo and name of the health information system that we are here to help improve. They use this truck to drive out to remote health facilities and support the system users. One type of vehicle that neither of us have seen yet &amp;amp;#8211; a firetruck!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 14:28:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/swazi-fire</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/swazi-fire</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Thanksgiving</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s a bit late. Sorry about that! We had tons of prep beforehand and cleanup after!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, Thanksgiving is not celebrated in Japan, surprise! Though some American holidays have been adopted a little, Thanksgiving is definitely not one of them. So to celebrate it, we invited the Alt’s and a few of the Japanese people that hang out with the Alt’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, we had 7 people come over (we invited more but several people backed out day of…). We structured the meal part as a potluck, we provided the turkey, mashed potatoes, and pies, and asked everyone else to bring sides and drinks. People brought gyōza, mac and cheese, camel corn, and a variety of other favorites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were waiting for people to arrive, we had Lilly’s switch set up for people to play Mario kart, which people seemed to enjoy. We also just hung out and talked a bunch. No football though! We don’t even own a TV!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Turkey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did end up finding turkey at Costco in Sendai, so I got to defrost, prepare, cook, and serve a turkey for the first time. It was an interesting process, especially because the bird only just barely fit both in our fridge and later in our oven. Everyone seemed to enjoy it so it was worth it! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/1-Tukey-in-refridgerator.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The turkey only fit when we removed the drawers and had it pushed all the way back&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/2-turkey-next-to-oven.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;And the turkey just barely fitting in our oven! We had to cover the top with foil after a bit because it was too close to the heating elements and was just starting to burn.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/3-ghee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Ghee bath for the turkey after it had roasted for a while. Never made ghee like this before, only super huge quantities for Greek Fest. *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/4-roasted-turkey.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Final image before carving and serving. I think it turned out pretty well all things considered!*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desserts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilly wanted to make two desserts: apple cobbler and pumpkin pie. Cobbler is pretty easy and she’s made some very yummy cobbler several times before. As expected, the cobbler was delicious! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/5-apple-crisp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*The apple cobbler Lilly made! Yum!*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more challenging dessert was the pumpkin pie. Usually pumpkin pie isn’t too challenging as long as you can make a good crust, but we faced a different challenge here: no pumpkins….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weeelllll, I guess that’s not quite fair to say. Japan has, “pumpkins” in that they have a squash they call pumpkin, but it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/12/IMG_6444-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Green Japanese &amp;amp;#8220;pumpkin&amp;amp;#8221;*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with Japanese pumpkin is that it simultaneously has less sugar and water but more starch than what we’re used to in the States. This means that pretty much no recipe will work as the ratios are all wrong. We had to try several different variations of different recipes before we finally found something that works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it’ll mean much to people to give a complete recipe, but the biggest changes we made were as follows: add more sugar, boil the squash like mashed potatoes to get as much liquid as possible, and food process it a decent bit to smooth everything out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/6-pie-crust.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Lilly&amp;amp;#8217;s pie crust, an important first step and challenging when there&amp;amp;#8217;s a giant turkey in the fridge. *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/7-first-pie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Pie #1, though we burned it a bit&amp;amp;#8230; Still tasted good though after we scrapped the black off. *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/8-second-pie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Pie #2, less burnt and still super good! *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/9-plated-pie-with-whipped-cream.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Plated with a dollop of hand-whipped cream (we don&amp;amp;#8217;t have an electric mixer) *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Everything Else&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night went very well! People had fun, the food was all good, we enjoyed the company – overall a good night! The mashed potatoes and mac and cheese were well received as American classics, and since most of the Alt’s don’t cook so they’ve missed out! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/10-mashed-potatos.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Mashed potatoes *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/11-food-table-and-lillys-aloe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Food table including Lilly&amp;amp;#8217;s aloe*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/kotatsu-with-bread-11-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*The kotatsu that we ate on/under, it kept us warm and toasty! *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/12-selfie-with-everyone-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*All the people! *&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/13-turkey-deconstruction.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;*Turkey disassembly after all was said and done*&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 02:28:12 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/thanksgiving</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/thanksgiving</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>The beach!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So Lilly and I have been fairly busy, but I’ll put together a few blog posts now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620051847729950.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week we went to the beach in Minamisanriku, an area hit pretty hard in the tsunami in 2011. In fact, the beach only reopened for public use last year. It’s a pretty nice little town though and the beach was very nice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620061068116910.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620065373985152.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few food stalls setup on one end of the beach, so we got snacks there first before going swimming. We went with a few other ALTs as we didn’t have our car yet, so we had to wait around a bit while the others tried to find us. Once we had all arrived we sunscreened up and jumped in the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620065047991630.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beach was pretty warm and the water was refreshing, not warm but definitely not cold. It was apparently Lilly’s first time swimming in a non-hypothermia inducing ocean, so she got to learn about mouthfuls of salt water and the like. For those not in Oregon, we have beaches but they’re very cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we swam for a while, we decided to make a sand castle while we waited for some late arrivers to make it. The kids on the beach seemed to think it was pretty funny watching a bunch of adult foreigners trying to build a sandcastle too close to the water. After we finished building it, we decided to try and keep it alive until the others joined us, so we had to build large walls to protect it from the incoming tide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One the last few people arrived, we did a tad more swimming and eating before heading over to a shrine that was attached to an island from the end of the beach. The hike was fairly steep but not too long or muddy despite recent rain. The shrine was neat but rather small and plain. The small island was hit pretty hard in the tsunami as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620064558563612.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620057981055770.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620056995674421.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620058423314147.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620062782109164.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards we did a bit more swimming before heading over to a small market nearby. Some shops were closed because last week was Oban (a weeklong festival), but we did grab some stuff from a cute bakery. After that we headed to a coffee shop in Tome that the ALTs really like before heading home for the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 23:52:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/the-beach</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/the-beach</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>The halfway point</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s strange how the pace of life is notoriously slower here and yet for us it feels like there’s a mountain of work and never enough hours in the day. Some of that can be attributed to necessary daily rituals such as cooking, washing dishes, hanging laundry out on the line. There’s very little prepackaged convenience foods so meals require more food prep. We are so lucky that we live close to the central shopping area of Mbabane, but it still takes longer to walk to the stores and back than it would to do it by car (not to mention that we have to carry all of those groceries up the hill!). I don’t mind the chores though since they seem like a natural and essential part of the daily life. The more difficult part is the office work. There’s a constant level of frustration because the “right way” of doing things is often completely impractical here. You will have a time sensitive email that needs to be sent ASAP, but the internet is down (or the power is out). Last week we had a flash flood. I couldn’t cross the road to get to a meeting in the building right across the street because the road had turned into white water rapids! Funding is always on the verge of being pulled away from the project and the cut backs are crippling our efforts. There’s never enough hands to make the work light. Despite these challenges, our coworkers are excited about the direction of the project. It may not happen quickly, but progress is being made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also amazing how long six months can feel. I really can’t focus on the total time remaining because it seems unbearable to be away from family and friends for so long. But, one more day seems manageable. So, I am taking it one day at a time!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 14:20:17 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/the-halfway-point</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/the-halfway-point</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Tihar, Midterms, and Cooking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The title is roughly in order, but midterms spanned several weeks across our classes, so that makes midterms actually overlap Tihar and cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_4479.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Let’s begin with a gratuitous puppy picture.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, first was Tihar! Nobody seems to know the origins of the word, but Tihar in Nepal is equivalent to Deepawali or Diwali, the Festival of Lights, celebrated across South Asia. It’s five days long, with specific times to worship/recognize crows, dogs, cows, oxen, the goddess of wealth, and brothers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_4541.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tihar marigolds for sale by the stupa&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being the Festival of Lights, nearly everyone displays brightly colored lights, often more than what you’d see during Christmas in the States. It’s inherently hard to take pictures of, but all the big businesses had 50+ foot-long string lights hanging from the roof down the walls. Additionally, this is the main holiday for fireworks. Compared to American Independence Day, Tihar involves many more firecrackers, and many fewer mortars, fountains, smoke bombs, and sparklers. That along with amplified music late into the night made it hard to sleep!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_4561.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The city all lit up&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the day for crow worship, people put food out for the birds. For the days for dogs, cows, and oxen, those animals get tikka (red forehead dot), good food, and marigold necklaces. For Laxmi, the goddess of wealth, everyone makes a sand mandala on the street outside their house or shop, with a line going inside. This is a greeting to invite the goddess in. For brother worship, sisters put tikka on their brothers. For some reason, we received tikka from our host grandma, and instead of just the red, it was a full rainbow! We also received a gift tray with nuts and fruits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_4552.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mouthy Girl enjoying her Kukur Tihar&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_4540.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Street dogs all dressed up for their fancy meal&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/f571572d-d115-4113-be2f-8d4b591590b2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A large-ish sand mandala for Laxmi Puja&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the holiday, we lit fireworks and rockets on the roof, played cards, danced, and took a drive around the city to tour the lights, all with our host family! It was the most interaction we’ve had since our first day at this house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_4613.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bhaaii Tikka&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next topic: midterms. It’s important to note that the classes here are far from what I’m used to. Computer science lectures, homework, and exams have little in common with anthropology, Nepali language, and analysis of Buddhist texts. We’ve had to do much more memorization than we’re used to, but it’s working out pretty well so far! Many topics are organized in lists, so we need to memorize the content and order of the “eight branches of this” and the “twelve links of that” and the “four types of that other thing” on topics ranging from types of refuge to the physical requirements to generate the supreme virtue (bodhicitta).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, midterms went well overall. We haven’t gotten all of our scores back yet, but it’s pretty easy to gauge performance yourself with these things; you either know it or you don’t, and if the test asks what you know, you’re good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, cooking! Living with a modern Brahmin family these days usually wouldn’t mean much, but our host grandma is on the traditional side of things. As we mentioned earlier, we weren’t allowed to cook. However, apparently our homestay coordinator spoke with our host family recently, and they concluded that it’s okay for us to venture into the kitchen every once in a while. We are very confused about how this change of policy came to be, but we aren’t complaining. Today, for the first time ever (in Nepal), we cooked our own meal in our own home! It was just a simple stir fry, but navigating someone else’s kitchen is an order of magnitude more difficult when you don’t even know what utensils are normal to have!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the first time cooking in Nepal, though. First, we “cooked” a “meal” at a friend’s apartment that ended up much less organized than we expected. For the second cooking experience, we made momos (Nepali dumplings filled with cabbage+onion+parsnip+soy+garlic+ginger and dipped in spicy tomato-sesame sauce) at another friend’s house. Since that second friend lives in a homestay of her own, that was the first Brahmin kitchen we used. The momo-making process was quite labor-intensive, but well worth it for the delicious result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_4523.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Momos!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concluding&lt;/strong&gt; thoughts, in no particular order:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re over halfway done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s November and still short-sleeve weather. It was actually almost too warm today. We found an article about someone complaining about climate change and Nepal’s “never-ending summer”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that it’s stopped raining with the end of the monsoon season, there’s nothing to keep the dust out of the air. It just blows around and gets in your eyes and lungs. We have face masks, but they can only help so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_4438.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We continue to teach weekly swing dance classes.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While shopping for ingredients, the only tofu we found was unwrapped and sitting in a tub of water… very questionable sanitation. We cooked and ate it anyway. We’ll let you know if we die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/img_4664.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reaching in&amp;amp;#8230;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finally took a walk around the oasis of wealth that is the 5-star hotel Hyatt Regency Kathmandu! It’s only a fifth of a mile from our house, but it’s walled off, so we hadn’t found a way in before. This time, we went with a friend who has a swimming membership and can therefore get past the guards. We had fun breathing the fresh air among the plants, gazing at the lavish lobby, walking on the jogging track, seeing the pool, and *ahem* playing on the playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/4e0893aa-9d30-4624-bffe-bb637db395cd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ooh la la.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of October 22, Kendrea is reunited with her laptop! The repair was covered by a recall, so we didn’t have to pay anything. She is greatly enjoying the brand-new display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can’t repair the wifi, though, so for those of us in Eswatini and Nepal, uploading pictures takes practically as long as writing the actual blog post. We hope you appreciate them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw the Himalayas from our rooftop! We thought they were out of view behind the foothills, but it turns out we can get a peek when the clouds, pollution, and dust are out of the way at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/11/b6bf7e65-51df-4b79-b4fc-d300d83e5fa0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Those are totally mountains! (Photo taken through binoculars)&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 06:39:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/tihar-midterms-and-cooking</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/tihar-midterms-and-cooking</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Tokyo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We landed at Narita International Airport at 1:45pm our time, and were ushered through lots of volunteers to get our bags shipped to Tome and our persons to the hotel. We then had a 90 min bus ride to Shinjuku, Tokyo where we checked into our room. When all was said and done, it was about 5:30 and we decided to go get some ramen. We ran to a 7-11 to grab onigiri, and then went and had some yummy ramen at a nearby restaurant. The food was fast, cheap, and quite yummy! Finally, we headed back to the hotel and grabbed some mochi skewers with red bean paste on top 🍡.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re pretty tired, but we got to see some country-side as we bused in and we got to do just a little bit of exploring. We’re definitely ready for a good night’s sleep!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190804_1927434572737870080536004680.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190804_1927252087819699291457688217.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 05:40:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/tokyo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/tokyo</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Tokyo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As some of you may already know from other blog posts, we had my entire immediate family come visit us in Japan for Christmas! My parents wanted to spend some time in Japan being a tourist on their way out to meet up with us (they arrived 5 days before Gabriel and Kendrea) so they looked into various attractions in Narita (where they landed), Tokyo (where they could catch a train to Sendai), and other places along the way. In their research, they found a site claiming that the Emperors palace is open on December 23rd due to it being the Emperors birthday. Since the palace is pretty much always closed to the public, Lilly and I thought that sounded really neat and wanted to go see the palace as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In preparation for the trip, Lilly found a good AirBNB house that was a bit on the outskirts of Tokyo but still had train access. This allowed us to have easy access to Tokyo without needing to pay tons of money to actually be in Tokyo. The house was two stories and had two bedrooms, pretty much a perfect match for our needs! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/airBNB-house-outside.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Outside of the AirBNB house, we had the whole thing to ourselves.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those that aren’t aware, our apartment in Tome is about 5 hours north of Tokyo by car, and there are tolls along the way that add up to almost $100! That said, it’s still cheaper than buying two Shinkansen ( 新幹線 : bullet train) tickets as those are over $100 per person. It is a pretty drive though, with lots of mountains along the way. Though we didn’t get to appreciate the views very much as we left around 5am in an attempt to get to Tokyo around 10 am alternated sleeping in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traffic didn’t quite play along nicely as we got into Tokyo, and we had to stop and get gas, so it ended up being closer to 11 am by the time we made it to the house. From there, Lilly and I left the car parked in the lot at the house and took the train to Tokyo Station to meet up with my parents. We didn’t quite time things right with them and ended up waiting at the station for a bit before my parents arrived, but they did finally make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner that night we went to yakiniku ( 焼肉 : grilled meat) which is similar to Korean BBQ in the States, except that they don’t use Korean spices or cuts of meat. One of the favorites was gyūtan (牛タン : cow tongue) which has almost no fat, marbled or otherwise, unlike most cuts of meat in Japan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/Yakinikuwiki.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Traditional grills have live coals under a wire grill and people use metal tongs to grill the food&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/Gyutan_teishoku.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gyūtan with the usual cuts to make the meat a little more edible. Yakiniku gyūtan is usually cut pretty thin to allow it cook faster, though we&amp;amp;#8217;ve gotten it thick like this at places before&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Sunday, we went to Nikorai-do ( 復活大聖堂 or ニコライ堂 : Holy Resurrection Cathedral or Nikolai’s House). The cathedral is the seat of Metropolitan Daniel of the Japanese Orthodox Church, though he was actually at the hospital that day and we didn’t get to see him. As such, it wasn’t a hierarchical service, but it was still very nice and the choir was very good! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/Holy_Resurrection_Cathedral_in_Tokyo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View as you walk up to the cathedral. It used to be on a hill overlooking the city, but then the city came up and engulfed the church.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/holy-resurrection-cathedral.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Iconostasis inside. The choir stands off on the right, and confessions happen on the left before the service starts. Also, the reliquary at the edge on the right side of the picture has a relic of St. Nicholas of Japan for people to venerate.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were very welcoming at the church and even provided us with a sheet of paper that had the epistle and gospel reading in English! There’s also a deacon from America that serves at the cathedral and he did a litany in English. We were less fortunate with the priests giving confession, but they knew enough to ask our names, verify we were orthodox, and give a blessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilly and I would like to go back to Nikorai-do at some point for a service with the Metropolitan serving, but that will have to be another trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the service we found some breakfast that didn’t have gluten and then walked around the part of Tokyo that the church is in, as well as took a trip down the train line a bit to see more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/sunday-walking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Selfie overlooking a channel as we were walking to Akihabara&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first place we went was Akihabara (秋葉原) as it’s within walking distance from the church. Though known for a few things, we were mostly interested in the electronics part. We found a few hole-in-the-wall type shops, one of which ended up being a super packed little mall (complete with escalators) with tons of different types of shops inside. A lot of the shops were closed since it was Sunday, but we did get to see some fun and interesting stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/akihabara-neo-geo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A free Neo-Geo (no coins required) tucked away in a small shop in Akihabara&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending some time poking around shops, we went to the Edo-Tokyo Museum to see some history for the area. The museum covers from 1590 through 1964 showing everything from models of the city layout; to artifacts like clothing, pottery, and buildings; to old electronics; to school lunches through the years. We thought the museum was really cool, so here’s a bunch of photos!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/edo-museum-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/edo-museum-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/edo-museum-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/edo-museum-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/edo-museum-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/edo-museum-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/edo-museum-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final part of our Sunday was a trip to Sensō-ji temple (金龍山浅草寺) and the impressive Kaminarimon Gate (雷門) leading up to the temple. The area directly behind the gate has a whole bunch of shops (though we apparently didn’t get any pictures of that part), and after them another gate, followed by shops selling stuff more closely related to the temple, and finally the temple itself. Buddhist temples have lots of gold in the inside, though people don’t really go into the temples and shrines in Japan except for ceremonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/Kaminarimon-across-the-street.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/kaminarimon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/three-americans-under-the-lamp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/garden-Buddha.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/another-gate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/senso-ji-temple-shops.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/senso-ji-temple-pagoda.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/second-gate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/inside-the-temple.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended our day getting dinner at a nearby restaurant and got to introduce a few more interesting Japanese dishes as well as absorb more cigarette smoke than I think I have in my entire life up until now combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday was supposed to be our day to visit the Emperor’s Palace, but apparently that wasn’t to be. Since the old Emperor abdicated this year, his son ascended the throne and the new day is some time in February…. Not exactly compatible with our plans for the day! So since our original plans were foiled, we had to find some other things to fill the day with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first thought was to go to Ueno Park (上野公園) and visit either the zoo or the one of the museums there, but apparently lots of things that stay open on the weekend choose Monday to be their day off. So pretty much everything in Ueno Park was closed. The only thing in the park that we could see was the shrine, so we poked our heads in and took a quick look around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/ueno-shrine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This building at the Ueno Park shrine has clearly had a new copper roof put on. Nice and shiny!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Ueno Park, we hopped back on the train and took a trip to the old black market district Ameya-Yokochō (アメヤ横丁). This was pretty much the only open air market we’ve seen like it in Japan thus far. There were lots of seafood stalls, meat stalls, some stalls selling trinkets and American-style goods, and some restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/ameya-yokocho.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/grilled-and-smoked-meat-stall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/sea-food-stall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/another-seafood-stall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there we took a train down to the Tokyo Skytree (東京スカイツリ) which is the tallest tower, and the second largest structure in the world (according the Wikipedia anyway). In the basement of the train station there, we saw a very cool candy making shop that had someone making candy as people watched. We then went upstairs and found lunch at some food carts at the base of the tower. They even had some gluten free food which was good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/Tokyo_Skytree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/candy-maker.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/finished-candy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/hard-candy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that we started our long trip home, but we did stop briefly along the way at Kawagoe (川越市), specifically Koedo (小江戸) which means “Little Edo” as it’s the only surviving section of Edo period Tokyo. The houses and shops all date back to the 1600’s or earlier! We didn’t get to look around that much as it was late and most everything was closed, but we did get to see some really neat old buildings and we did stop at an open shop to look around a bit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2020/01/45914575071_bf2b4cbc0c_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Koedo at night, lots of old wooden buildings!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry this was a long post, we packed a lot into those three days! It was the longest trip Lilly and I have taken from home and we definitely trust our little “Kei” car much more now that’s it’s proven that it can make long trips. We’re definitely going to have more road trips as we explore more of Japan!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 08:03:37 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/tokyo-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/tokyo-2</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Tome City – 登米市</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is our fourth day in Japan, and it’s been a bit of a long one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before today, yesterday Damian and I had a chance to spend time with a very good friend of mine, Yurika, who I’ve known since high school. It had been a very long time since I’d seen her and we had a really good time hanging out together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190806_1814278615816779221992284.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished up the last of the Tokyo Orientation yesterday, and this morning we checked out bright and early to make our way with a group of other Miyagi JETs to Sendai, the capital of Miyagi Prefecture. We got on the shinkansen, or bullet train, at about 8 am, after spending a lot of time walking and riding trains through Tokyo with quite a bit of baggage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190807_0858413783443139244958917.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the shinkansen, we walked to the Sendai board of education to greet and be greeted by the people in charge. We also met my supervisor, the extremely helpful and resourceful Sato-san. He has helped us immensely, preparing numerous items and lots and lots of information to make our transition as smooth as possible. He’s our hero!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the BOE in Sendai, Sato-san and another JET ALT named Kai drove us and our fellow Tome JET to Tome proper, where we finished the process to declare our residency in Tome. Finally, we headed over to our very, extremely, ridiculously empty apartment. I will dedicate another post to the apartment itself, but for now I will leave you with this lovely shot of Damian in a doorway of our new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/img_20190807_1742050425863277084361632052.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 07:29:53 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/tome-city-%25e7%2599%25bb%25e7%25b1%25b3%25e5%25b8%2582</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/tome-city-%25e7%2599%25bb%25e7%25b1%25b3%25e5%25b8%2582</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Umhlanga (Reed Festival)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Monday we went to one of the biggest (or maybe &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; biggest?) celebration in eSwatini: Umhlanga, that is, the Reed Festival. Young maidens march from their villages to collect reeds which they then take to the Queen Mother’s palace to be used to build up the outer wall. They march 30km (10km for the younger ones) in regiments often while singing, then camping out for during the nights. The explanation is that the festival will encourage them to remain sexually inactive, show reverence for the queen, and build solidarity. The entire ceremony is 8 days with the girls marching, cutting the reeds, presenting them to the queen, and preparing for days 6 and 7 where they dance. On day 7 they dance at an arena within the royal compound with spectators and the king present. On the 8th day the king commands cows to be slaughtered and the girls receive a portion of the meat and head back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stress on the virginal aspect of it (in modern days) relates to their efforts to reduce the transmission of HIV. They also encourage men to be celibate. Their rate of infection is the highest in the world and they are working very hard to bring that down. There is already a measurable improvement in their new infection rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen and I took a khumbi from Mbabane to the event, a trip of about 40 minutes or so. On the way, we chatted a little with a guy sitting next to me. It turns out he’s from Rwanda and he was very helpful knowing when to get off, where to go, and what was happening!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the khumbi stop at the dead end of a dirt road, we starting walking down a path that quickly opened up into another road. Along the road were dilapidated houses and shops, litter, and an inexplicable stream of water running down the center. Despite its humble look, we felt safe and only experienced friendliness or indifference from the residents. We were among &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; other people heading to the royal residence. It was a bit striking how close this area was with such contrast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190902_124941-1-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large numbers of people passed through on their way&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spotted an untethered cow, and then a chicken as we walked. Both ignored us. I don’t think anyone tethers their chickens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190902_124952-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A random chicken pecking around for bugs&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked past a large number of shops selling clothing and housewares, along with small food stands selling various grilled meats, french fries (or &lt;em&gt;chips&lt;/em&gt; as they say in UK fashion), and fruits and vegetables. We walked a decent distance not having any idea what we were looking for exactly or when we would arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190902_125710-1-1024x390-1024x390.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point we heard the sound of many people. We turned around to see a large number of people coming toward us — the first group! As they got closer, we could hear that they were singing. It continues to amaze us how wonderful the singing in eSwatini is. This was no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190902_1258222-1024x600-1024x600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The colorful decorations of the maidens were quite striking&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Girls were divided into groups of 8-13 year olds and 14-22 year olds. Regiments each had their own uniforms and song that they sang. I can only imagine that there must have been months of preparation leading up to the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190902_130501-1-1024x429-1024x429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Groups are accompanied by up to four men to supervise and keep them safe on the journey&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the girls had on garments that went around their waists and often shoulders or arms. It was a minimum of clothing which probably felt good in the hot sun. There is much pride in the outfits, and the topless nature of it looks from the outside to be evidence of positive body image, and a sense of empowerment. This isn’t about being sexually alluring — it’s about them being themselves and embracing their femininity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190902_1312232-1024x768-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The girls were clearly having fun and many excitedly wanted to be photographed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once at the arena, the girls marched around the field, in front of the spectators, then to the back where they stayed. Groups sang and danced as they walked past. The field got more and more full as the afternoon wore on. There was so much great singing and excitement. Smiles were found not only on the field, but all around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was very cute seeing the really young girls (I think perhaps too young to participate) running out from the stands to march with them anyway, then running back even happier. Pairs and small groups of them would gather together and walk around the stands perhaps going between different people they knew in the seats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/MVIMG_20190902_160258-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/MVIMG_20190902_154500-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/MVIMG_20190902_1530182-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/MVIMG_20190902_1342493-1024x575.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190902_142102-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190902_1440512-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/MVIMG_20190902_1503402-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, the king came down and did his own dance and went around inspecting the groups. Some years he chooses a wife from those assembled, but not this year. I’m not really sure how all of that works but there is also input from his mother and various advisers so I don’t think it’s as simple as just seeing a pretty girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to see why this is such an important event for the Swazi people. It’s a wonderful showing of national pride and clearly an exciting event for the girls who participate. I’m glad we were able to see it during our time here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 14:37:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/umhlanga-reed-festival</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/umhlanga-reed-festival</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Waterfalls and zebras</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We had a great trip on Saturday! We took a khumbi for a 30 minute ride to Malolotja Nature Reserve. It was an adventure just getting there since we weren’t entirely sure where to get off! Once there, we hiked around and explored under the watchful eyes of lots of gazelles (or impalas, we weren’t sure…). There were interesting rocks and lots of ups and downs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_145610-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arian sitting there oh-so-casually&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was beautiful with good views. It was a hot day, but there were good breezes, especially on the hilltops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_145724-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Karen resting in the shade&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the rocks, we saw lots of flowers in bloom as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_152130-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Not sure what this, but it&amp;amp;#8217;s on the cover of the Eswatini Visitor&amp;amp;#8217;s Guide so it must be special!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few kilometers, we got to a lookout point where we thought we’d see the famed Malolotja Falls (highest in the country). It turned out that the overlook didn’t actually provide any view… so that was disappointing. It was a beautiful view of the plains and valleys though. As we looked left, we noticed movement. We assumed it was more of the impalas or gazelles we kept seeing, but then we realized that we were seeing a herd of zebras! They were pretty far off, so I decided to try to approach them to get some photos. I walked slowly, and followed Karen’s advice to keep looking at the ground and ambling around more than just walking straight and looking at them. My ploy failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_153741-1-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Look at that! You see those zebras right? Just a few hundred meters away but still just specks in the picture.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every minute or so they’d start kicking up dust and jumping around, settling down a little farther away. Eventually, I gave up. Unfortunately, as with many cell phone cameras, I can’t really zoom so I don’t have any decent pictures to share. A real camera/lens combo would have yielded some great shots!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past the zebras, we walked downhill, toward the waterfall. It was quite a bit farther than we’d hoped (even though we were warned!). It was a beautiful landscape, but much drier and open than we’re used to. We saw a sign for Ibis nesting. It said trail closed, but we had already been told by a ranger to ignore it. I’m assuming it just hadn’t been taken down yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_154121-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Piles of rocks were used for trail markers in a number of places. In case you can&amp;amp;#8217;t tell the where the animal paths lead&amp;amp;#8230;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final part of the hike was a steeper decline. We got about halfway down and decided it was far enough since we could see it! We stood by an edge and got some shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_155807-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;You can see the water flowing toward the right. You can&amp;amp;#8217;t tell, but it&amp;amp;#8217;s quite a bit farther down to get there. This is why a need a good 3d camera&amp;amp;#8230;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn’t look that impressive from there, but we didn’t think it was a good idea to keep going and have to retrace that much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_155930-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Peeking over the cliff edge we can see the waterfall way down below. Any farther down would feel 10x worse going back up!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we returned, we came across a patch of grass that was noticeably more lush. Getting closer we could tell that it was damp, saturated ground. Being on an incline and seeing this, with no stream or other water nearby seemed odd! Upon closer inspection, we saw that the water was bubbling up from under a rock! It was a little spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_162607-Custom-1024x769-1024x769.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way back, I had to take a picture of the road. Talk about parched land! Despite the river and waterfall only a few kilometers away, there was no water here…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_165319-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the last leg of our hike, we noticed some very unusual rocks. I’ve never seen cracks like these before, especially in so many rocks. I’m not sure what it means, but I know that Eswatini is supposed to be notable for geological reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_170838-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some of the rocks with interesting cracks&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made our way back to the road and had to wait a few minutes for the khumbi. The sun was starting to dip down so we started getting worried, but soon enough a ride came by! It was a fun day and we’re glad to have gotten to see some more of Eswatini’s natural beauty. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190921_173320-1024x469-1024x469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;About six khumbis passed us the other direction before one came our way!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 14:58:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/waterfalls-and-zebras</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/waterfalls-and-zebras</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>We thought our lives would be simple</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, it’s been a while!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Back to School!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we last spoke, Gabriel and I have had a full week of school! In no particular order…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We went on a field trip today in our Buddhist History and Culture class. We walked five minutes down the road to a grand monastery that we hadn’t seen before. All 44 students settled into a small temple with three huge golden statues (sorry, no pictures allowed!) and read (aloud and in unison) the Buddha’s narration of his own enlightenment. What an excellent way to take advantage of the school’s location! Right behind us, several monks performed a puja (ceremony). We’d like to say that the traditional Tibetan horns playing in the background created a lovely spiritual atmosphere, but no, they were just super loud and clashed obnoxiously. Maybe we’ll grow to like them??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can now write in Devanagari (the Nepali alphabet)! Nepali class is definitely the most fun and engaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Khenpo class is neat. It’s less organized than I expected — a learned Tibetan monk just talks about a text (“The Way of the Bodhisattva” by Shantideva), word by word, for 1.5 hours every day. We enjoy hearing his belly laugh, stories, friendly dialogue with the translator, and of course his vast stores of teachings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gabriel had his first Anthropology of Nepalese Religions class today with Fr. Greg. He says it was “superb”, so especially because I’ve taken a Buddhist Ethics class at OSU already, I think I’ll switch out of Ethics to join Anthropology! I also plan to switch out of Buddhist History and Culture to join Fundamentals of Buddhist Philosophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Saturday, we had exactly the sort of immersive experience we’d hoped for! First, we attended a 3.5-hour teaching by the esteemed Chökyi Nyima Rinpoche. He radiates compassion, and we received plenty of it because we sat in the very front with the other new students. He runs a 500-monk monastery, RYI, an online dharma training program, several dharma institutions outside of Nepal, a charity that helps people and animals in Nepal, and perhaps Earth. We would have enjoyed the teaching more if he hadn’t arrived a half hour late and we hadn’t been sitting painfully on the floor the entire time… After the teaching, we met up with three classmates to work on a reflection paper over a phở lunch by the stupa. We had an amazing two-hour discussion with a nun of Korean heritage from New York, a nun from the Nepali side of the Himalayas, and a laywoman from the Kathmandu Valley. The first nun had zero patience for Western academic analysis of Buddhism, which was fascinating to hear and to (very sensitively) argue against. At one point, she gave a little speech about dance in Buddhism that perfectly mirrored something that Gabriel’s priest uncle had said to us a couple months ago about singing in Orthodox Christianity. All in all, super cool, and now we have a few new friends. (Tiring, though… I fell asleep at 6:30pm that night.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So much Buddhism. Although we’re glad that we’ve set aside four months to study this fascinating subject, we definitely look forward to returning to computer science once we get home! This is actually the perfect situation — we’re diving into another culture while affirming our career paths.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/c2c6eaaf-52a4-46d7-b3cd-ce635d830bd0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beard trimming on our balcony&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Boudha Community Choir&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found a choir!! Good news for my mental health!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We rehearse weekly at someone’s house. The choir has about 30 members, mostly from America and Europe. Many of them attend or teach at RYI. We’re preparing for a Christmas concert, and I think the choir is somehow associated with a local church; it’s really nice to have some exposure to familiar Western Christian culture. The choir isn’t gonna win any advanced musicianship awards, but that’s okay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best part: we’re singing “Bogoroditse Devo”. During our wedding two months ago, the wedding choir sang it for us as we entered the church. So excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Swing Society&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We taught a dance class! Yuki is an accomplished dancer and fellow member of the Corvallis Swing Society. She had the idea and motivation to begin a Swing Society at RYI. On Sunday, she, Gabriel, and I taught the basics of single-count swing to three students (we’ll advertise better for next week) in the monastery restaurant’s meditation/activity room. They learned a ton in a short time, we hung out with a stray dog, I remembered to bring my portable speaker, we ran home in the pouring monsoon rain in the dark, and we had lots of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some slight updates/clarifications/corrections about the home situation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gabriel and I, as outcastes, are not allowed to be involved in the process of cooking in this high-caste (Brahmin) Hindu house. It’s fine if we are in the kitchen area. Our bedroom is ours, but the kitchen and dining room belong to the grandma. Her house, her rules. I have to let her know when I’m on my period so that she can serve me food in a room off to the side — if I touched the dining table while I was on my period, I’d pollute it. (According to our Nepali language professor, many Brahmins these days are no longer this strict about purity.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The grandma has at least three “helpers”: Saili (always around), Laxmi (sometimes around), and a lady I just met today who apparently works in the garden. All of them are Brahmins. This explains why they are allowed to help in the kitchen!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again, all the purity stuff is Hindu; Buddhism doesn’t have castes. I’m writing about it because it’s striking to us, and it’s probably more interesting to read about than the way that Nepalis do their laundry or something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roshan’s 12-year-old son, Pragoon, comes over pretty often, too. He and Ishan (Milan’s son; Pragoon’s cousin) are very close, and they play video games on their tablets together all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We still interact with only the grandma 90% of the time, and then only over meals. I really hope that we don’t seem antisocial!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Real Talk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After three weeks, my body is still having a hard time adapting to the new country. Sitting on the ground hurts — I’m not sure whether to blame weak back muscles or scoliosis. I’ve needed a lot of sleep: upwards of 9 hours every day. The humidity makes us sweat and makes the scary-disease-carrying mosquitos happy. I’m glad that we aren’t expected to go on adventures across the city now that orientation is over, because those taxed me to my physical and mental limit. Gabriel and I have both had mild colds and severe headaches. We’re very glad that we haven’t had any stomach bugs or severe illnesses (yet)! Sometimes we’ve struggled to find enough time alone to recharge our introverted selves. We’ve had to adapt to different food: the current meal plan is a large serving of dal bhat tarkari (rice or flatbread, lentils, and various vegetable curries) in the morning, a small serving of whatever-the-monastery-restaurant-happens-to-have-today at 12:30, and another large serving of dal bhat tarkari in the late evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say all this not to complain, but to show that moving across the world has physical consequences, even if you don’t get sick! Travelers, please take care; people at home, enjoy your ability to more easily take care 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/1901114b-174e-4096-bf3d-8edc2cf9b035.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beautiful monsoon light and a rainbow&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:28:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/we-thought-our-lives-would-be-simple</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/we-thought-our-lives-would-be-simple</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>We’re alive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just in case anyone was concerned that we haven’t posted for a little bit, we just wanted to assure everyone that we are alive! We haven’t made it to any festivals recently and we’re still trying to figure out some of the basics that didn’t come with our apartment (we finally got a real stove, still working on an oven, got internet sorted, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190913_050139909-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunrise from our front window&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do have a few larger posts in the works, but it’s taking some time to collect some good pictures and to make sure we have enough experience to actually write a good post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to our person stuff: we’re doing alright! My work is going well and I’ve not had any issues remoting to Oregon (other than that I’m not really a morning person and 5am is definitely the morning!). Lilly is getting into the groove of normal teaching stuff and today is visiting her first kindergarten. We’re both excited about the addition of a stove since it means that we can finally cook more than one thing at once!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/IMG_20190901_083705777_HDR-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On the road to Ishinomaki&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also planning some visits to other parts of Japan, so keep an eye on the blog in the next few weeks. Lilly has some 3 day weekends that we’re going to make good use of, possibly going to a ryokan (旅館) or traditional inn with tatami matted rooms and public baths in the Sendai area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we’ve got some plans for the next few weeks, we’re finally getting our apartment setup more, and we’re definitely still alive, we just haven’t done anything terribly interesting for a week or two (sorry).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 18:52:54 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/were-alive</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/were-alive</guid>
              </item>
                <item>
        <title>Yosakoi Festival</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620060304160428.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since all of last week was a holiday, there were lots of festivals all over the place for different things depending on the day. There were a bunch of fireworks festivals later in the week, but on Sunday afternoon was a dance festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the festival mid afternoon and as we walked up, there was a very intense group of girls (middle school I think?) from one of the local schools performing in the streets. This style of dance involves moving forward quite far, so the festival was setup at a T intersection: the top part of the T was where two different groups would perform separately as they moved toward the middle, the bottom of the T was a large main stage where different groups would perform, and the intersection of the T was where all the food stalls were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620059892093720.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We grabbed a bit of food and watched a bunch of different performances, we were both super impressed with the flag waving. Each troup had 1-3 flag wavers at the back of the group and their flags were huge. I can’t imagine how much strength it must have taken to wave the flags like they were, but they were all ripped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620055345127226.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620065945534896.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620061995000440.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived right at the end of all the performances, so we got to see the big finale where all the troupes performed together twice, and then afterwards all the flag bearers came out, they introduced all the groups, then did a performance with just the flags twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620059165701877.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620064066246897.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620063487202828.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/line_620061505219089.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if Lilly will approve of me uploading these, but there was also a group all the way from Hokkaido (some from Sendai as well, this was apparently a well known event) who took things up a notch. At one point in their main performance, the men all stripped down to their loin clothes and finished the dance like that. Of course during the combined performance at the end, they excitedly repeated that aspect of their show for everyone to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/download_20190823_142255.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/download_20190823_142249.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.kulpfamily.org/assets/2019/10/download_20190823_142251.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:23:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/sites/family/yosakoi-festival</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sites/family/yosakoi-festival</guid>
              </item>
            </channel>
</rss>
